{
    "questions": [
        {
            "id": 3001,
            "question": "Retrolental fibroplasia is a complication of:",
            "options": [
                "chemotherapy",
                "hydrotherapy",
                "radiotherapy",
                "physiotherapy",
                "oxygen therapy"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3002,
            "question": "Cardioversion may be indicated in the treatment of:",
            "options": [
                "complete AV block",
                "digitalis toxicity",
                "atrial fibrillation",
                "multifocal atrial tachycardia",
                "repeated short lived tachycardias"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3003,
            "question": "Parkinsonian side effects of phenothiazine are best treated with:",
            "options": [
                "haloperidol",
                "lorazepam (Ativan)",
                "chlordiazepoxide",
                "benztropine mesylate",
                "lithium carbonate"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3004,
            "question": "The etiologic agent in molluscum contagiosum (painless/small/firm/umbilicated/white surface papules) is:",
            "options": [
                "RNA virus",
                "DNA virus (poxvirus)",
                "chlamydia trachomatis",
                "staphylococcus aureus",
                "papilloma virus"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3005,
            "question": "Ruptured Baker's cyst (which causes a painful swelling of the popliteal fossa) is most to be seen in:",
            "options": [
                "osteoarthritis",
                "gout",
                "ankylosing spondylitis",
                "rheumatoid arthritis",
                "psoriatic arthritis"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3006,
            "question": "Heparin effect is neutralized by:",
            "options": [
                "warfarin sodium",
                "protamine sulphate",
                "phenylbutazone",
                "streptokinase",
                "tissue type plasminogen activator"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3007,
            "question": "The most common breast tumor is:",
            "options": [
                "papillary carcinoma",
                "medullary carcinoma",
                "inflammatory carcinoma",
                "infiltrating ductal scirrhous carcinoma",
                "fibroadenoma"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3008,
            "question": "Carcinoma of the prostate is treated with:",
            "options": [
                "tolazamide",
                "prednisone",
                "bromocriptine",
                "androgen",
                "estrogen"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3009,
            "question": "Atropine poisoning is treated with:",
            "options": [
                "amitriptyline",
                "epinephrine",
                "pilorocaprine",
                "neostigmine",
                "physostigmine"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3010,
            "question": "Imipramine is indicated in treatment of following disorders, EXCEPT:",
            "options": [
                "acute panic disorder",
                "acute mania",
                "major depression",
                "enuresis",
                "cataplexy"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3011,
            "question": "Sprengel's deformity is a congenital elevation of:",
            "options": [
                "hip",
                "patella",
                "scapula",
                "sternum",
                "clavicle"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3012,
            "question": "7 year old boy presents with right upper thigh and right knee pain when walking, the most likely diagnosis is:",
            "options": [
                "Kohler's disease",
                "Osgood Schlatter's disease",
                "Legg Calve Perths' disease",
                "congenital dislocation of the hip",
                "slipped capital femoral epiphysis"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3013,
            "question": "Osteogenesis imperfecta (brittle bones) is NOT associated with:",
            "options": [
                "deafness",
                "tall stature",
                "blue sclerae",
                "bone fragility",
                "skull deformity"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3014,
            "question": "Regarding osteoarthritis, which of the following is TRUE?",
            "options": [
                "usually affects small joints",
                "more common in men than in women",
                "joint pain is precipitated by exertion",
                "more common in thin and athletic people",
                "onset is generally before 40 years of age"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3005,
            "question": "Ruptured Baker's cyst (which causes a painful swelling of the popliteal fossa) is most to be seen in:",
            "options": [
                "osteoarthritis",
                "gout",
                "ankylosing spondylitis",
                "rheumatoid arthritis",
                "psoriatic arthritis"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3006,
            "question": "Heparin effect is neutralized by:",
            "options": [
                "warfarin sodium",
                "protamine sulphate",
                "phenylbutazone",
                "streptokinase",
                "tissue type plasminogen activator"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3007,
            "question": "The most common breast tumor is:",
            "options": [
                "papillary carcinoma",
                "medullary carcinoma",
                "inflammatory carcinoma",
                "infiltrating ductal scirrhous carcinoma",
                "fibroadenoma"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3008,
            "question": "Carcinoma of the prostate is treated with:",
            "options": [
                "tolazamide",
                "prednisone",
                "bromocriptine",
                "androgen",
                "estrogen"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3009,
            "question": "Atropine poisoning is treated with:",
            "options": [
                "amitriptyline",
                "epinephrine",
                "pilorocaprine",
                "neostigmine",
                "physostigmine"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3010,
            "question": "Imipramine is indicated in treatment of following disorders, EXCEPT:",
            "options": [
                "acute panic disorder",
                "acute mania",
                "major depression",
                "enuresis",
                "cataplexy"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3011,
            "question": "Sprengel's deformity is a congenital elevation of:",
            "options": [
                "hip",
                "patella",
                "scapula",
                "sternum",
                "clavicle"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3012,
            "question": "7 year old boy presents with right upper thigh and right knee pain when walking, the most likely diagnosis is:",
            "options": [
                "Kohler's disease",
                "Osgood Schlatter's disease",
                "Legg Calve Perths' disease",
                "congenital dislocation of the hip",
                "slipped capital femoral epiphysis"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3013,
            "question": "Osteogenesis imperfecta (brittle bones) is NOT associated with:",
            "options": [
                "deafness",
                "tall stature",
                "blue sclerae",
                "bone fragility",
                "skull deformity"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3014,
            "question": "Regarding osteoarthritis, which of the following is TRUE?",
            "options": [
                "usually affects small joints",
                "more common in men than in women",
                "joint pain is precipitated by exertion",
                "more common in thin and athletic people",
                "onset is generally before 40 years of age"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3015,
            "question": "3 months after a measles infection, a 7 year old boy develops seizures, the most likely diagnosis is:",
            "options": [
                "phenylketonuria",
                "subarachnoid hemorrhage",
                "benign febrile seizures",
                "maple syrup urine disease",
                "subacute sclerosing panencephalitis"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3016,
            "question": "12 year old boy presents with fever and bilateral parotid enlargement, the most likely diagnosis is:",
            "options": [
                "mumps",
                "sarcoidosis",
                "typhoid fever",
                "acute leukemia",
                "mixed (pleomorphic) tumor of parotid"
            ],
            "answer": "a",
            "answer_index": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 3017,
            "question": "Hypertension is most likely to be associated with:",
            "options": [
                "mastocytosis",
                "Addison's disease",
                "cardiac tamponade",
                "carcinoid syndrome",
                "Recklinghausen's disease (neurofibromatosis)"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3018,
            "question": "Short PR interval and normal QRS interval without a delta wave are seen in:",
            "options": [
                "hypokalemia",
                "hypermagnesemia",
                "first degree heart block",
                "Lown-Ganong-Levine syndrome",
                "Wolf-Parkinson-White syndrome"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3019,
            "question": "A baby turns blue whenever stops crying, the most likely diagnosis is:",
            "options": [
                "lung abscess",
                "cystic fibrosis",
                "mitral stenosis",
                "choanal atresia",
                "tetralogy of Fallot"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3020,
            "question": "Which of the following should be ruled out in a 15 year old boy with gynecomastia?",
            "options": [
                "Down's syndrome",
                "Edward's syndrome",
                "Turner's syndrome",
                "fragile X syndrome",
                "Klinefelter's syndrome"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3021,
            "question": "Children with pectus excavatum (funnel breast) are most likely to develop:",
            "options": [
                "kyphosis",
                "sarcoidosis",
                "osteosarcoma",
                "cystic hygroma",
                "achondroplasia"
            ],
            "answer": "a",
            "answer_index": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 3022,
            "question": "X-ray of lateral neck of a 6 year old child shows thumb-print sign, the most likely diagnosis is:",
            "options": [
                "croup",
                "epiglottitis",
                "cystic fibrosis",
                "bronchial asthma",
                "epiglottal cancer"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3023,
            "question": "Croup (laryngotracheobronchitis) is:",
            "options": [
                "most commonly caused by fungus",
                "associated with inspiratory stridor",
                "usually occur in ages 10 to 15 years",
                "more common in males than in females",
                "characterized by high fever for 3 days"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3024,
            "question": "A man with barrel-chest and a long history of shortness of breath on exertion, the most likely diagnosis is:",
            "options": [
                "emphysema",
                "pneumothorax",
                "bronchial asthma",
                "bronchial cancer",
                "iron deficiency anemia"
            ],
            "answer": "a",
            "answer_index": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 3025,
            "question": "The best test for a child with pneumonia, nasal polyps, and meconium ileus is:",
            "options": [
                "sweat test",
                "Guthrie test",
                "secretin test",
                "nasal challenge test",
                "glucose tolerance test"
            ],
            "answer": "a",
            "answer_index": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 3026,
            "question": "Giant cell pneumonia is most likely to occur following:",
            "options": [
                "mumps",
                "rabies",
                "tetanus",
                "measles",
                "impetigo"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3027,
            "question": "Half-and-half nails (white proximal half and pink or brown distal half) is most likely to occur in:",
            "options": [
                "psoriasis",
                "hepatic cirrhosis",
                "respiratory disease",
                "iron deficiency anemia",
                "renal disease with azotemia"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3028,
            "question": "Risk factors for developing acute renal failure include:",
            "options": [
                "jaundice",
                "anesthesia",
                "increased age",
                "ECF volume contraction",
                "all of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3029,
            "question": "Which of the following is LEAST likely to occur in end-stage renal failure?",
            "options": [
                "anemia",
                "hematuria",
                "proteinuria",
                "hypertension",
                "large kidney size"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3030,
            "question": "SIADH is associated with:",
            "options": [
                "oat cell carcinoma",
                "thymoma",
                "pneumonia",
                "encephalitis",
                "all of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3031,
            "question": "SIADH is associated with:",
            "options": [
                "Hodgkin's disease",
                "tuberculosis",
                "brain tumor",
                "head trauma",
                "all of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3032,
            "question": "Regarding Q fever, which of the following is TRUE?",
            "options": [
                "is a rickettsial disease",
                "caused by coxiella brunetii",
                "spread mainly by inhalation",
                "has an incubation period of 1 to 3 weeks",
                "all of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3033,
            "question": "Patients with hepatitis B virus (HBV) may develop:",
            "options": [
                "polyarteritis nodosa",
                "hepatocellular carcinoma",
                "serum sickness-type syndrome",
                "membranous glomerulonephritis",
                "all of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3034,
            "question": "Regarding hepatitis B virus (HBV), which of the following is TRUE?",
            "options": [
                "incubation period is between 20 to 30 days",
                "individuals with HBsAg are highly infectious",
                "about 60% of infected patients become chronic carriers",
                "the incidence peaks in the 15 to 19 year old age groups",
                "all of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3035,
            "question": "Regarding hepatitis A virus (HAV), which of the following is FALSE?",
            "options": [
                "mortality rate is less than 0.1%",
                "diagnosis is based on serologic tests",
                "incubation period is between 2 to 6 weeks",
                "patients are most infectious prior to or during the icteric stage",
                "the finding of IgG anti-HAV antibodies indicates recent infection"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3036,
            "question": "HTLV-1 and 2 are most likely to cause:",
            "options": [
                "erythema infectiosum",
                "Creutzfeld-Jakob disease",
                "infectious mononucleosis",
                "T cell leukemia and lymphoma",
                "decreased CD4 cells and immunosuppression"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3037,
            "question": "Regarding molluscum contagiosum, which of the following is FALSE?",
            "options": [
                "rare in children",
                "caused by poxvirus",
                "nodules are usually painless",
                "treated with liquid nitrogen",
                "spread by contact or sexual intercourse"
            ],
            "answer": "a",
            "answer_index": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 3038,
            "question": "Subcutaneous nodule at injury site with associated nodular lymphangitis which appears up to 6 months is seen in:",
            "options": [
                "carbuncle",
                "candidiasis",
                "blastomycosis",
                "sporotrichosis",
                "scalded skin syndrome"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3039,
            "question": "Dinner fork deformity is associated with:",
            "options": [
                "Mallet's finger",
                "Colles' fracture",
                "Smith's fracture",
                "Gamekeeper's fracture",
                "Dupuytren's contracture"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3040,
            "question": "The most common wrist fracture in young adults is:",
            "options": [
                "hamate fracture",
                "pisiform fracture",
                "capitate fracture",
                "trapezium fracture",
                "scaphoid (navicular) fracture"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3041,
            "question": "Ulna is fractured in (nightstick fracture) and in:",
            "options": [
                "Pott's fracture",
                "Boxer's fracture",
                "Mallet's fracture",
                "Bennett's fracture",
                "Monteggia's fracture"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3042,
            "question": "Roseola infantum (exanthema subitum) is caused by:",
            "options": [
                "Epstein-Barr virus",
                "cytomegalovirus (CMV)",
                "varicella-zoster virus",
                "herpes simplex virus (HSV)",
                "human herpesvirus-6 (HHV-6)"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3043,
            "question": "Following could be caused by Epstein-Barr virus, EXCEPT:",
            "options": [
                "Alport's syndrome",
                "Burkitt's lymphoma",
                "acute mononucleosis",
                "chronic fatigue syndrome",
                "nasopharyngeal carcinoma"
            ],
            "answer": "a",
            "answer_index": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 3044,
            "question": "Which of the following has been reported to be associated with Guillain-Barre syndrome?",
            "options": [
                "helicobacter pylori",
                "campylobacter jejuni",
                "klebsiella pneumonia",
                "borrelia burgdorferi",
                "pseudomonas aeruginosa"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3045,
            "question": "Which of the following viruses is associated with hepatoma?",
            "options": [
                "HPV",
                "RSV",
                "EBV",
                "HIV",
                "HBV"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3046,
            "question": "Progressive multifocal leukoencephalitis (PML) is caused by:",
            "options": [
                "HIV",
                "EBV",
                "RSV",
                "JC virus",
                "adenovirus"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3047,
            "question": "Weakness of knee extension is caused by lesion at:",
            "options": [
                "L3-L4",
                "L4-L5",
                "L5-S1",
                "S1-S2",
                "S2-S3"
            ],
            "answer": "a",
            "answer_index": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 3048,
            "question": "Weakness of knee flexion is caused by lesion at:",
            "options": [
                "L3-L4",
                "L4-L5",
                "L5-S1",
                "S1-S2",
                "S2-S3"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3049,
            "question": "Weakness of great toe flexion is caused by lesion at:",
            "options": [
                "L3-L4",
                "L4-L5",
                "L5-S1",
                "S1-S2",
                "S2-S3"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3050,
            "question": "Weakness of great toe extension is caused by lesion at:",
            "options": [
                "L3",
                "L4",
                "L5",
                "S1",
                "S2"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3051,
            "question": "Virus most commonly involved in pleurodynia, myocarditis and pericarditis is:",
            "options": [
                "adenovirus",
                "mumps virus",
                "coronavirus",
                "coxsackievirus B",
                "respiratory syncytial virus"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3052,
            "question": "Virus most commonly involved in pharyngitis is:",
            "options": [
                "adenovirus",
                "mumps virus",
                "coronavirus",
                "cytomegalovirus",
                "respiratory syncytial virus"
            ],
            "answer": "a",
            "answer_index": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 3053,
            "question": "The most common cause of granulomatous cervical lymphadenopathy in children is mycobacterium:",
            "options": [
                "marinum",
                "kansasii",
                "fortuitum",
                "scrofulaceum",
                "avium-intercellulare"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3054,
            "question": "Goats and sheep are most likely to transmit:",
            "options": [
                "yersinia",
                "brucella",
                "schistosoma",
                "giardia lamblia",
                "pasteurella multocida"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3055,
            "question": "Hansen's disease is diagnosed by:",
            "options": [
                "Ham's test",
                "Frei's test",
                "Coomb's test",
                "Lepromin test",
                "Schirmer test"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3056,
            "question": "Infants with cyanosis, respiratory distress, drooling saliva, choking and regurgitation immediately after birth is most commonly due to:",
            "options": [
                "tetralogy of Fallot",
                "aspiration pneumonia",
                "hyaline membrane disease",
                "bronchial asthma",
                "esophageal atresia"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3057,
            "question": "Following are contraindications for live measles vaccine, EXCEPT:",
            "options": [
                "antineoplastic and steroid therapy",
                "mitral stenosis",
                "allergy to neomycin",
                "immunodeficiency disorders",
                "systemic malignancy"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3058,
            "question": "Following are absolute contraindications to further pertussis vaccination, EXCEPT:",
            "options": [
                "high fever",
                "collapse state",
                "encephalopathy",
                "unusual high-pitched cry",
                "family history of seizures"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3059,
            "question": "Which of the following is a familial disorder of Hartnup's disease characterized by hypercalcemia and nephrocalcinosis?",
            "options": [
                "cretinism",
                "alkaptonuria",
                "Wilson's disease",
                "blue-diaper syndrome",
                "progressive muscular dystrophy"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3060,
            "question": "Mentally retarded child with protruding belly, large head, membranous corneal veil, thick lips and tongue, the most likely diagnosis is:",
            "options": [
                "congenital hypothyroidism",
                "Down's syndrome",
                "gargoylism",
                "Wilson's disease",
                "progressive muscular dystrophy"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3061,
            "question": "Following are side effects of estrogen therapy, EXCEPT:",
            "options": [
                "nausea",
                "headache",
                "weight loss",
                "breast tenderness",
                "menstrual bleeding"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3062,
            "question": "Following are absolute contraindications for renal biopsy, EXCEPT:",
            "options": [
                "hydronephrosis",
                "nephrotic syndrome",
                "bleeding diathesis",
                "renal hemangioma or tumor",
                "renal abscess or large cysts"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3063,
            "question": "Which of the following is contraindicated in the management of acute pancreatitis?",
            "options": [
                "atropine",
                "meperidine",
                "morphine",
                "calcium sulphate",
                "serum albumin"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3064,
            "question": "A pregnant woman with vaginal bleeding and cramps but her pregnancy continues, the most likely diagnosis is:",
            "options": [
                "inevitable abortion",
                "incomplete abortion",
                "missed abortion",
                "threatened abortion",
                "complete abortion"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3065,
            "question": "In polycystic ovary syndrome (Stein Leventhal syndrome):",
            "options": [
                "both FSH/LH are increased",
                "FSH is normal/LH is increased",
                "FSH is increased/LH is normal",
                "both FSH/LH are decreased",
                "none of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3066,
            "question": "Oliguria is associated with:",
            "options": [
                "renal tubular acidosis",
                "Fanconi's syndrome",
                "lithium therapy",
                "hypercalcemia",
                "congestive heart failure"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3067,
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT seen in hemolytic uremic syndrome?",
            "options": [
                "anuria/oliguria with acute renal failure",
                "thrombocytopenia/hemolysis",
                "hematuria/edema/hypertension",
                "positive Coombs test",
                "anemia/fragmented WBCs/fibrin deposition in kidneys"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3068,
            "question": "The most common cause of empyema is:",
            "options": [
                "staphylococcus aureus",
                "streptococcus pyogenes",
                "escherichia coli",
                "pneumococcus (streptococcus pneumoniae)",
                "pseudomonas aeruginosa"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3069,
            "question": "Major depression with melancholia may be diagnosed by:",
            "options": [
                "CT scan of the head",
                "electroencephalography",
                "X-ray of the head",
                "dexamethasone suppression test",
                "none of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3070,
            "question": "Alkaptonuria (ochronosis) is due to deficiency of the enzyme:",
            "options": [
                "cytathionine synthase",
                "fructose 1-phosphatase",
                "homogentisic oxidase",
                "alpha L-iduronidase",
                "acid lipase"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3071,
            "question": "Self-examination of the breast should be advised to:",
            "options": [
                "postmenopausal women only",
                "nulliparous women only",
                "women with history of mammary dysplasia only",
                "all women over age 50 only",
                "all women over age 30"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3072,
            "question": "Following are common psychiatric disorders seen in the elderly, EXCEPT:",
            "options": [
                "schizophrenia",
                "depression",
                "hypochondria",
                "anxiety",
                "paranoid ideation"
            ],
            "answer": "a",
            "answer_index": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 3073,
            "question": "Following are characteristics of ketoacidosis (ketosis/acidosis in IDDM), EXCEPT:",
            "options": [
                "hypernatremia",
                "rapid deep breathing",
                "low arterial blood pH",
                "low plasma bicarbonate",
                "hyperglycemia/hypotension"
            ],
            "answer": "a",
            "answer_index": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 3074,
            "question": "Cheilosis is particularly common in association with deficiency of:",
            "options": [
                "thiamine (B1)",
                "niacin",
                "pantothenic acid",
                "riboflavin (B2)",
                "folic acid"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3075,
            "question": "Which of the following types of nails is most likely to be seen in patients with nephrotic syndrome/hypoalbuminemia?",
            "options": [
                "yellow nails",
                "Mees' lines (transverse lines)",
                "Terry's nail (white proximal two thirds)",
                "Beau's lines (horizontal nail depression)",
                "Muehrcke's nails (two horizontal white stripes)"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3076,
            "question": "Sudden pain with rapidly increasing scrotal enlargement, relieved by elevation of the scrotum is most likely to be caused by:",
            "options": [
                "spermatocele",
                "testicular torsion",
                "hydrocele",
                "acute epididymitis",
                "testicular neoplasm"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3077,
            "question": "The progress of the disease in insulin dependent diabetes mellitus (IDDM) is best detected by:",
            "options": [
                "glucose tolerance test",
                "serum fructosamine",
                "glycosylated hemoglobin",
                "ketonuria",
                "glycosuria"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3078,
            "question": "In patients with pregnancy induced hypertension, which treatment is usually administered?",
            "options": [
                "reserpine or labetol",
                "clonidine or propanolol",
                "nifedipine or diazoxide",
                "hydralazine or methyldopa",
                "captopril or nitroprusside"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3079,
            "question": "Chronic anal fissure is the most common cause of painful defecation and is LEAST likely to be associated with:",
            "options": [
                "constipation",
                "rectal bleeding",
                "pruritus ani",
                "sentinel pile",
                "hypertrophied papilla"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3080,
            "question": "True statement regarding urinary tract infection (UTI) includes:",
            "options": [
                "in neonates/infants is more common in girls than in boys",
                "after 5 years of age is more common in girls",
                "bacteriuria during adolescence is more common in boys",
                "the incidence of UTI in women decreases with age",
                "of all ages, UTI is more common in males than in females"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3081,
            "question": "Long term schizophrenia is best treated with supportive psychotherapy combined with:",
            "options": [
                "benzodiazepine",
                "lithium carbonate",
                "amphetamine",
                "phenothiazine",
                "naloxone"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3082,
            "question": "The most common cause of hemoptysis in children is:",
            "options": [
                "lung cancer",
                "pneumonia",
                "foreign body",
                "pulmonary embolism",
                "bronchiectasis"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3083,
            "question": "A bluish pigmentation spot over the lower back or buttocks of a dark-skinned infant may suggest the diagnosis of:",
            "options": [
                "milia",
                "capillary hemangioma",
                "petechiae",
                "Mongolian spot",
                "lanugo"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3084,
            "question": "Close personal contacts of patients with hepatitis A should receive:",
            "options": [
                "rifampin",
                "hepatitis B vaccine",
                "gamma globulin",
                "corticosteroids",
                "none of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3085,
            "question": "Following are features of cretinism (juvenile hypothyroidism), EXCEPT:",
            "options": [
                "delayed bone age",
                "stippling of epiphysis on bone X-ray",
                "pot belly with umbilical hernia",
                "increased serum cholesterol",
                "decreased serum TSH"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3086,
            "question": "Following are associated with anorexia nervosa, EXCEPT:",
            "options": [
                "hypercholesterolemia",
                "osteoporosis",
                "hypercarotenemia",
                "tachycardia",
                "hypothermia"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3087,
            "question": "The initial symptoms of Lyme disease are regional lymphadenopathy and:",
            "options": [
                "facial nerve palsy",
                "cardiac arrhythmia",
                "skin lesion",
                "back pain",
                "joint pain"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3088,
            "question": "Intentionally avoiding thinking about disturbing problems, wishes, feelings, or experiences is called:",
            "options": [
                "dissociation",
                "sublimation",
                "undoing",
                "splitting",
                "suppression"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3089,
            "question": "Marjolin ulcer:",
            "options": [
                "is an advanced gastric ulcer",
                "occurs in secondary syphilis",
                "is a malignant intestinal lesion caused by trauma",
                "is a malignant skin lesion in a burn scar",
                "is a basal cell carcinoma in a burn scar"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3090,
            "question": "The most common cause of dysphagia is:",
            "options": [
                "achalasia",
                "scleroderma",
                "esophageal varices",
                "esophageal carcinoma",
                "esophageal stricture"
            ],
            "answer": "a",
            "answer_index": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 3091,
            "question": "11 year old boy with reddish purple patches on the eyelids and rash over the dorsum of the hands, your diagnosis is:",
            "options": [
                "atopic dermatitis",
                "dermatomyositis",
                "psoriasis",
                "scleroderma",
                "dermatitis herpetiformis"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3092,
            "question": "Approximately 40% of patients with coarctation of the aorta have:",
            "options": [
                "tricuspid atresia",
                "mitral valve disease",
                "bicuspid aortic valve",
                "tetralogy of Fallot",
                "subclavian steal syndrome"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3093,
            "question": "Whipple operation is used in surgical treatment of the carcinoma of:",
            "options": [
                "lung",
                "pancreas",
                "bladder",
                "spleen",
                "kidney"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3094,
            "question": "Pulsus paradoxus (decreased systolic BP > 10mmHg during inspiration) is NOT a clinical feature of:",
            "options": [
                "pulmonary embolism",
                "hypovolemia",
                "myocarditis",
                "pericarditis",
                "asthma"
            ],
            "answer": "a",
            "answer_index": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 3095,
            "question": "Following are associated with hirsutism (hypertrichosis), EXCEPT:",
            "options": [
                "Cushing's syndrome",
                "hyperprolactinemia",
                "congenital adrenal hyperplasia",
                "granulosa cell ovarian tumor",
                "acromegaly"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3096,
            "question": "Following are promoters of the absorption of iron, EXCEPT:",
            "options": [
                "gastric acid",
                "sugar",
                "alcohol",
                "cereals",
                "ascorbic acid"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3097,
            "question": "The best investigation for a child with recurrent bronchiolitis, nasal polyps, malabsorption and failure to thrive is:",
            "options": [
                "bronchography",
                "pulmonary function tests",
                "blood gases",
                "sweat chloride test",
                "lung scan"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3098,
            "question": "Following are risk factors for acute pancreatitis, EXCEPT:",
            "options": [
                "hyperparathyroidism",
                "family history of pancreatitis",
                "hypocalcemia",
                "thiazide diuretic therapy",
                "estrogen therapy"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3099,
            "question": "Which of the following types of polyps of colon is usually a premalignant lesion?",
            "options": [
                "hyperplastic",
                "juvenile",
                "adenomas",
                "inflammatory",
                "hamartomas"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3100,
            "question": "The most common presentation of symptomatic Meckel's diverticulum is:",
            "options": [
                "vomiting",
                "abdominal pain",
                "abdominal distention",
                "painful rectal bleeding",
                "painless rectal bleeding"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3101,
            "question": "The first stage in dying patients is:",
            "options": [
                "anger",
                "acceptance",
                "bargaining",
                "denial",
                "depression"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3102,
            "question": "A woman presents with serosanguinous discharge from the nipple, your diagnosis is:",
            "options": [
                "carcinoma",
                "mammary dysplasia",
                "fibroadenoma",
                "intraductal papilloma",
                "abscess"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3103,
            "question": "The most useful investigation for a patient with flank pain, fever and hematuria is:",
            "options": [
                "liver biopsy",
                "muscle biopsy",
                "cystoscopy",
                "intravenous pyelogram",
                "urine culture"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3104,
            "question": "Undescended testicles (cryptorchidism) usually descent:",
            "options": [
                "immediately after birth",
                "between second-fourth month of life",
                "during the first nine months of life",
                "between first-third year of life",
                "before one month of age"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3105,
            "question": "The most common site of tinea versicolor is:",
            "options": [
                "intertriginous areas",
                "face/scalp",
                "upper/lower extremities",
                "upper trunk/neck",
                "fingers/toes"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3106,
            "question": "The first symptom of Paget's carcinoma of the breast is:",
            "options": [
                "bleeding",
                "superficial erosion",
                "ulceration",
                "itching/burning",
                "palpable mass"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3107,
            "question": "Abortion is defined as termination of gestation before the:",
            "options": [
                "5th week of pregnancy",
                "10th week of pregnancy",
                "15th week of pregnancy",
                "20th week of pregnancy",
                "25th week of pregnancy"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3108,
            "question": "Pruritus is LEAST likely to be associated with:",
            "options": [
                "acne vulgaris",
                "pregnancy",
                "hyperthyroidism",
                "carcinoid syndrome",
                "cholestasis"
            ],
            "answer": "a",
            "answer_index": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 3109,
            "question": "A swollen epididymis due to epididymitis is differentiated from testicular tumor initially by:",
            "options": [
                "X ray",
                "ultrasound",
                "technetium scan",
                "testicular biopsy",
                "none of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3110,
            "question": "Which of the following is contraindicated in treatment of digitalis induced tachyarrhythmia?",
            "options": [
                "potassium chloride",
                "phenytoin",
                "propanolol",
                "quinidine",
                "synchronized DC shock"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3111,
            "question": "The first step in ophthalmoscopic examination is to look for:",
            "options": [
                "cloudiness of the vitreous",
                "disorders of the iris",
                "abnormalities in the aqueous",
                "red fundus reflection",
                "lesions on cornea"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3112,
            "question": "In ovarian failure:",
            "options": [
                "both FSH/LH are increased",
                "FSH is normal/LH is increased",
                "FSH is increased/LH is normal",
                "both FSH/LH are decreased",
                "none of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "a",
            "answer_index": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 3113,
            "question": "Primary prevention includes:",
            "options": [
                "breast cancer screening",
                "smoking cessation",
                "cholecystectomy",
                "radiotherapy",
                "none of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3114,
            "question": "Following are features of Kawasaki syndrome (mucocutaneous lymph node syndrome), EXCEPT:",
            "options": [
                "generalized pruritus",
                "maculopapular red rash",
                "high fever",
                "peeling of the fingers",
                "angitis of coronary arteries"
            ],
            "answer": "a",
            "answer_index": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 3115,
            "question": "Following are associated with hyperprolactinemia, EXCEPT:",
            "options": [
                "stress/sleep/depression",
                "hypothyroidism",
                "diabetes mellitus",
                "reserpine therapy",
                "nipple stimulation"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3116,
            "question": "The first step in the management of ruptured abdominal aortic aneurysm is:",
            "options": [
                "laparoscopy",
                "blood cross match",
                "abdominal X ray",
                "electrocardiogram",
                "abdominal CT scan"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3117,
            "question": "Following are side effects of isoniazid (INH), EXCEPT:",
            "options": [
                "central nervous system toxicity",
                "peripheral nervous system toxicity",
                "hepatotoxicity",
                "nephrotoxicity",
                "jaundice/skin rash"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3118,
            "question": "Fine downy growth of hair over the shoulder and back of a newborn is called:",
            "options": [
                "lanugo",
                "capillary hemangioma",
                "petechiae",
                "vernix caseosa",
                "milia"
            ],
            "answer": "a",
            "answer_index": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 3119,
            "question": "Acute orchitis (increased testicular size/erythema /fever) in adolescents is usually due to:",
            "options": [
                "leprosy",
                "schistosomiasis",
                "tuberculosis",
                "syphilis",
                "mumps"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3120,
            "question": "The most common cause of primary hyperparathyroidism (usually asymptomatic) is:",
            "options": [
                "carcinoma of one parathyroid gland",
                "carcinoma of all parathyroid glands",
                "adenoma of one parathyroid gland",
                "adenoma of all parathyroid glands",
                "hyperplasia of all parathyroid glands"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3121,
            "question": "When verapamil IV (Isoptin) fails to treat paroxysmal atrial tachycardia, the drug of choice is:",
            "options": [
                "propanolol",
                "digoxin",
                "atropine",
                "procainamide",
                "lidocaine"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3122,
            "question": "The most common complications of acute pancreatitis are:",
            "options": [
                "jaundice/blindness/psychosis",
                "intraperitoneal bleeding/DIC",
                "abscess/pseudocyst formation",
                "pleural effusion/atelectasis",
                "gastrointestinal bleeding/acute tubular necrosis"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3123,
            "question": "In X-linked dominant disorders:",
            "options": [
                "both sexes are affected equally",
                "affected males have normal daughters but affected sons",
                "the trait is more severe in daughters than sons",
                "affected male transmits the trait only to his daughters",
                "males are affected twice as often as females"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3124,
            "question": "When one fragment of the bone is driven into the other side of fractured bone, this is called:",
            "options": [
                "comminuted fracture",
                "avulsion fracture",
                "impacted fracture",
                "compound fracture",
                "depressed fracture"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3125,
            "question": "70 year old man presents with a solitary midlateral pulsatile neck mass, the most likely diagnosis is:",
            "options": [
                "Graves' disease",
                "Hodgkin's disease",
                "Pancoast syndrome",
                "carotid body tumor",
                "sarcoidosis"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3126,
            "question": "The best treatment for hypernephroma is:",
            "options": [
                "preoperative chemotherapy/radical nephrectomy",
                "chemotherapy/radiotherapy",
                "preoperative irradiation/radical nephrectomy",
                "radical nephrectomy with chemotherapy",
                "radical nephrectomy with regional node dissection"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3127,
            "question": "Following are disorders transmitted from human to human by sexual route, EXCEPT:",
            "options": [
                "hepatitis B",
                "toxoplasmosis",
                "codylomata lata",
                "codylomata acuminata",
                "molluscum contagiosum"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3128,
            "question": "Following are features of seborrheic keratosis, EXCEPT:",
            "options": [
                "stuck on lesion",
                "autosomal dominant trait",
                "involvement of epidermis only",
                "superficial ulceration",
                "occurrence after 30 years of age"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3129,
            "question": "Following are features of mania, EXCEPT:",
            "options": [
                "excessive spending",
                "aggressive behavior",
                "hypoactivity",
                "exhibitionistic behavior",
                "reduction of sleep"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3130,
            "question": "High calcium, high phosphorus, high or normal alkaline phosphatase and low parathyroid hormone are most likely seen in:",
            "options": [
                "osteoporosis",
                "osteomalacia",
                "hyperthyroidism",
                "hyperparathyroidism",
                "Paget's disease of the bone"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3131,
            "question": "Keratoacanthoma closely resembles squamous cell carcinoma and is characterized by:",
            "options": [
                "very slow growth lesion",
                "very malignant lesion",
                "response to antibiotic therapy",
                "stuck on lesion",
                "central crater filled with keratin"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3132,
            "question": "Which of the following medications is safely administered to pregnant women?",
            "options": [
                "isoniazid",
                "streptomycin",
                "metronidazole",
                "tetracycline",
                "cortisone"
            ],
            "answer": "a",
            "answer_index": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 3133,
            "question": "The most common site of polyps of colon is:",
            "options": [
                "ascending colon",
                "discending colon",
                "transverse colon",
                "cecum/ileo cecal area",
                "sigmoid/rectum"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3134,
            "question": "The most common breast mass or lesion in 35 to 40 years old women is:",
            "options": [
                "Paget's disease",
                "mammary dysplasia (fibrocystic disease)",
                "fibroadenoma",
                "intraductal papilloma of the breast",
                "breast cancer"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3135,
            "question": "Penicillin therapy in pregnant women with syphilis prevents congenital syphilis in:",
            "options": [
                "10% of cases",
                "30% of cases",
                "50% of cases",
                "70% of cases",
                "90% of cases"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3136,
            "question": "A positive Mantoux test means the patient:",
            "options": [
                "has silicosis and Pott's disease",
                "not necessarily has tuberculosis",
                "has disseminated (miliary) tuberculosis",
                "is taking isoniazide for active tuberculosis",
                "has tuberculosis complicated by Hodgkin's disease"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3137,
            "question": "Which of the following was the cause of Black Death (a disease which killed 25 million Europeans 4 centuries ago)?",
            "options": [
                "brucella suis",
                "campylobacter",
                "yersinia pestis",
                "proteus vulgaris",
                "klebsiella pneumonia"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3138,
            "question": "Which of the following is transmitted mainly by human lice?",
            "options": [
                "brucellosis",
                "listeriosis",
                "psittacosis",
                "leptospirosis",
                "relapsing fever"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3139,
            "question": "Weil's syndrome is also known as:",
            "options": [
                "acute brucellosis",
                "ocular listeriosis",
                "chronic psittacosis",
                "chronic shigellosis",
                "icteric leptospirosis"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3140,
            "question": "Lymphadenopathy, hepatosplenomegaly and anemia are most likely due to:",
            "options": [
                "schistosoma",
                "giardia lamblia",
                "trypanosoma cruzi",
                "entamoeba histolytica",
                "visceral leishmaniasis"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3141,
            "question": "Apical aneurysms of the heart, megaesophagus and megacolon are associated with infections due to:",
            "options": [
                "schistosoma",
                "giardia lamblia",
                "trypanosoma cruzi",
                "entamoeba histolytica",
                "visceral leishmaniasis"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3142,
            "question": "Which of the following is LEAST likely to be transmitted by sexual contact?",
            "options": [
                "schistosoma",
                "giardia lamblia",
                "trypanosoma cruzi",
                "trichomonas vaginalis",
                "entamoeba histolytica"
            ],
            "answer": "a",
            "answer_index": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 3143,
            "question": "Cellophane tape test is used in the diagnosis of:",
            "options": [
                "schistosoma",
                "tinea saginata",
                "toxicara canis",
                "trichuris trichiura (whipworm)",
                "enterbius vermicularis (pinworm)"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3144,
            "question": "Down's syndrome has been linked to:",
            "options": [
                "Still's disease",
                "Refsum's disease",
                "Briquet's disease",
                "Hodgkin's disease",
                "Alzheimer's disease"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3145,
            "question": "Part of chromosome 5 is missing in:",
            "options": [
                "Turner's syndrome",
                "Cri-Du-Chat syndrome",
                "Huntington's syndrome",
                "Lesche Nyhan syndrome",
                "Wegener's granulomatosis"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3146,
            "question": "Abnormal vision with refractory errors is diagnosed by:",
            "options": [
                "tonometry",
                "slit lamp",
                "cover test",
                "pinhole test",
                "all of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3147,
            "question": "Oliver's sign (tracheal tug) is positive in:",
            "options": [
                "pericarditis",
                "hiatal hernia",
                "aortic aneurysm",
                "esophageal reflux",
                "carotid body tumor"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3148,
            "question": "Palpable mass in the right abdomen with absence of bowel sounds in the RLQ (Dance's sign) is pathognomonic for:",
            "options": [
                "midgut volvulus",
                "intussusception",
                "congenital megacolon",
                "mesenteric artery obstruction",
                "hypertrophic pyloric stenosis"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3149,
            "question": "32 year old man presents with intermittent right lower quadrant pain and perirectal abscesses, the most likely diagnosis is:",
            "options": [
                "diverticulitis",
                "Crohn's disease",
                "acute appendicitis",
                "ulcerative colitis",
                "carcinoma of colon"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3150,
            "question": "In patients with fat embolism syndrome, petechiae are found in:",
            "options": [
                "5 to 10%",
                "20 to 30%",
                "30 to 40%",
                "50 to 60%",
                "80 to 90%"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3151,
            "question": "HLA A3, B7, and B18 are associated with:",
            "options": [
                "Reiter's disease",
                "myasthenia gravis",
                "multiple sclerosis",
                "chronic active hepatitis",
                "gluten-sensitive enteropathy"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3152,
            "question": "Human leukocyte antigen B8 (HLA B8) is associated with:",
            "options": [
                "myasthenia gravis",
                "dermatitis herpetiformis",
                "gluten-sensitive enteropathy",
                "chronic active hepatitis",
                "all of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3153,
            "question": "Which of the following is increased in hypovolemic shock?",
            "options": [
                "urine flow",
                "pulse rate",
                "cardiac index",
                "blood pressure",
                "central venous pressure"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3154,
            "question": "Which of the following is LEAST likely to occur in children with cytomegalic inclusion disease?",
            "options": [
                "cataract",
                "jaundice",
                "retinitis",
                "macrocephaly",
                "optic atrophy"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3155,
            "question": "The most likely diagnosis of respiratory distress after birth in full-term infants with heart sounds heard to the right chest is:",
            "options": [
                "pyloric stenosis",
                "aspiration pneumonia",
                "hyaline membrane disease",
                "diaphragmatic hernia",
                "esophageal atresia"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3156,
            "question": "Hair-on-end appearance in the calvarium on skull X-ray is characteristically seen in:",
            "options": [
                "anencephaly",
                "sarcoidosis",
                "thalassemia",
                "hydrocephalus",
                "achondroplasia"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3157,
            "question": "The best blood group/type given to patients with unknown crossmatching is:",
            "options": [
                "O Rh+",
                "O Rh-",
                "A Rh+",
                "B Rh+",
                "AB Rh-"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3158,
            "question": "Varicella can develop after exposure to:",
            "options": [
                "mumps",
                "measles",
                "rubella",
                "tetanus",
                "shingles"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3159,
            "question": "Acute pericarditis is associated with all of the following, EXCEPT:",
            "options": [
                "severe chest pain",
                "friction rub",
                "ST segment elevations",
                "nausea/vomiting",
                "increased myocardial enzymes"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3160,
            "question": "The most common type of lung cancer associated with heavy cigarette smoking in males is?",
            "options": [
                "metastatic",
                "small cell",
                "alveolar cell",
                "adenocarcinoma/epidermoid",
                "none of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3161,
            "question": "The most common cause of nongonococcal proctitis in homosexual men is:",
            "options": [
                "cytomegalovirus",
                "staphylococcus aureus",
                "herpes simplex virus",
                "chlamydia trachomatis",
                "pseudomonas aeruginosa"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3162,
            "question": "Telescoping of a segment of bowel into the adjacent segment showing (E) sign on X-ray is seen in:",
            "options": [
                "Meckel's diverticulum",
                "congenital megacolon",
                "hypertrophic pyloric stenosis",
                "congenital duodenal atresia",
                "intussusception"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3163,
            "question": "Surgical treatment of tetralogy of Fallot is intended to increase the blood flow in the:",
            "options": [
                "aorta",
                "right ventricle",
                "pulmonary artery",
                "subclavian artery",
                "superior vena cava"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3164,
            "question": "Carcinoma of the esophagus/cervix most commonly are:",
            "options": [
                "adenocarcinoma",
                "squamous cell carcinoma",
                "transitional cell carcinoma",
                "metastatic carcinoma",
                "none of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3165,
            "question": "The drug of choice for the treatment of amebic liver abscess is:",
            "options": [
                "tetracycline",
                "streptomycin",
                "chloramphenicol",
                "erythromycin",
                "metronidazole"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3166,
            "question": "Osler nodes, Janeway lesions and Roth spots are seen in:",
            "options": [
                "infective endocarditis",
                "chronic pancreatitis",
                "ulcerative colitis",
                "viral hepatitis",
                "toxic shock syndrome"
            ],
            "answer": "a",
            "answer_index": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 3167,
            "question": "A mid or late diastolic low pitched mitral murmur (Austin Flint murmur) can be heard in:",
            "options": [
                "mitral stenosis",
                "ventricular septal defect",
                "severe aortic regurgitation",
                "mitral regurgitation",
                "tricuspid regurgitation"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3168,
            "question": "Which of the following is LEAST likely to be seen in rheumatic fever?",
            "options": [
                "skin rash",
                "arthritis",
                "pericarditis",
                "joint deformities",
                "increased antistreptolysin titer"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3169,
            "question": "Pleural effusion can be detected on anteroposterior chest X ray when pleural fluid is:",
            "options": [
                "10 mL",
                "20 mL",
                "100 mL",
                "150 mL",
                "250 mL"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3170,
            "question": "Which of the following is LEAST likely to be associated with lung cancer?",
            "options": [
                "arsenic",
                "nickel",
                "asbestos",
                "silicon dioxide",
                "petroleum"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3171,
            "question": "Chronic inhalation of cotton or linen dust is associated with:",
            "options": [
                "berylliosis",
                "bagassosis",
                "byssinosis",
                "sequoiosis",
                "suberosis"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3172,
            "question": "Eggshell calcifications on chest X ray is seen in:",
            "options": [
                "asbestosis",
                "pneumoconioses",
                "radiation pneumonitis",
                "bronchial asthma",
                "silicosis"
            ],
            "answer": "a",
            "answer_index": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 3173,
            "question": "The most common abdominal mass found in the neonatal period after the first week of life is:",
            "options": [
                "neuroblastoma",
                "splenomegaly",
                "hydronephrosis",
                "Wilm's tumor",
                "intestinal tumor"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3174,
            "question": "Which of the following tests is LEAST helpful in diagnosis of pulmonary hypertension?",
            "options": [
                "pulmonary function tests",
                "perfusion lung scan",
                "echocardiogram",
                "pulmonary angiography",
                "chest X ray"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3175,
            "question": "The most common cause of pneumonia in children over 5 years of age is:",
            "options": [
                "coxiella brunetii",
                "histoplasma capsulatum",
                "chlamydia trachomatis",
                "mycoplasma pneumoniae",
                "mycobacterium tuberculosis"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3176,
            "question": "The average life expectancy for patients with cystic fibrosis is:",
            "options": [
                "10 years",
                "20 years",
                "30 years",
                "40 years",
                "50 years"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3177,
            "question": "Which of the following medications worsens brochospasm and is contraindicated in patients with COPD or bronchial asthma?",
            "options": [
                "prednisone",
                "atropine sulphate",
                "aminophylline",
                "propanolol",
                "cromolyn sodium"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3178,
            "question": "Clubbing of the digits is LEAST likely to be caused by:",
            "options": [
                "bronchial asthma",
                "infective endocarditis",
                "idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis",
                "cyanotic congenital heart disease",
                "pulmonary arteriovenous malformation"
            ],
            "answer": "a",
            "answer_index": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 3179,
            "question": "The most common cause of congenital stridor is:",
            "options": [
                "laryngeal webs",
                "vocal cord paralysis",
                "laryngomalacia",
                "subglottic stenosis",
                "subglottic hemangioma"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3180,
            "question": "The leading cause of death from skin disease is:",
            "options": [
                "Bown's disease",
                "squamous cell carcinoma",
                "basal cell carcinoma",
                "malignant melanoma",
                "keratoacanthoma"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3181,
            "question": "Which of the following dermatologic disorder is more common in fishermen/meat handlers:",
            "options": [
                "erysipelas",
                "erythrasma",
                "erysipeloid",
                "pemphigus",
                "pityriasis rosea"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3182,
            "question": "The causative organism in erysipelas (Saint Anthony's fire) is:",
            "options": [
                "clostridium",
                "staphylococcus aureus",
                "escherichia coli",
                "streptococcus pyogenes group B",
                "virus"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3183,
            "question": "The causative organism in forunculosis is:",
            "options": [
                "klebsiella",
                "staphylococcus aureus",
                "escherichia coli",
                "clostridium",
                "bacteroides"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3184,
            "question": "Which of the following is contraindicated in treatment of chronic discoid lupus erythematosus?",
            "options": [
                "dapsone",
                "corticosteroids",
                "radiotherapy",
                "chloroquine",
                "quinacrine"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3185,
            "question": "The most common skin disorder is:",
            "options": [
                "dermatitis herpetiformis",
                "seborrheic dermatitis",
                "erythema multiforme",
                "acne vulgaris",
                "pityriasis rosea"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3186,
            "question": "Skin (Herald patch)/(Christmas tree) configurations are seen in:",
            "options": [
                "dermatitis herpetiformis",
                "seborrheic dermatitis",
                "erythema multiforme",
                "pemphigus",
                "pityriasis rosea"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3187,
            "question": "Acantholysis is a hallmark of:",
            "options": [
                "dermatitis herpetiformis",
                "psoriasis",
                "erythema multiforme",
                "pemphigus vulgaris",
                "bullous pemphigoid"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3188,
            "question": "Toxic epidermal necrolysis and Steven Johnson syndrome (erythema multiforme major) are most commonly produced by:",
            "options": [
                "amoxicillin",
                "ampicillin",
                "penicillin",
                "sulfonamides",
                "trimethoprim sulphamethoxazole"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3189,
            "question": "Generalized pruritus in patients on hemodialysis is usually due to:",
            "options": [
                "scabies",
                "uremia",
                "atopic dermatitis",
                "psoriasis",
                "lichen planus"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3190,
            "question": "Following are associated with carcinoid syndrome, EXCEPT:",
            "options": [
                "tricuspid regurgitation/pulmonic stenosis",
                "abdominal cramps/diarrhea",
                "mitral stenosis or regurgitation",
                "increased urinary 5 HIAA",
                "edema of head/neck"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3191,
            "question": "The initial treatment of back pain due to spinal cord compression by tumor mass is:",
            "options": [
                "surgical excision",
                "chemotherapy",
                "radiotherapy",
                "corticosteroids",
                "none of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3192,
            "question": "Following diseases are more common in the elderly, EXCEPT:",
            "options": [
                "tuberculosis",
                "craniopharyngioma",
                "polymyalgia rheumatica",
                "herpes zoster infection",
                "cataracts/otosclerosis"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3193,
            "question": "The most common cause of bilateral vocal cord paralysis is:",
            "options": [
                "brain stem lesion",
                "supranuclear lesion",
                "thyroidectomy",
                "cortical lesion",
                "congenital central lesion"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3194,
            "question": "Which of the following dermatologic disorders may associate with lesions of the oral cavity?",
            "options": [
                "lichen planus",
                "keratoacanthoma",
                "tinea versicolor",
                "erythrasma",
                "erysipeloid"
            ],
            "answer": "a",
            "answer_index": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 3195,
            "question": "The most common cause of facial (peripheral seventh nerve) paralysis is:",
            "options": [
                "acoustic neuroma",
                "Guillain Barre syndrome",
                "surgical trauma",
                "Bell's palsy",
                "temporal bone fracture (trauma)"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3196,
            "question": "The most common cause of tinnitus (sensation of noise in the ear) is:",
            "options": [
                "ototoxicity",
                "presbycusis",
                "acoustic neuroma",
                "congenital aneurysms",
                "temporal bone fracture"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3197,
            "question": "In sensorineural deafness, air conduction threshold and bone conduction threshold are:",
            "options": [
                "unequally increased",
                "equally increased",
                "unequally decreased",
                "equally decreased",
                "none of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3198,
            "question": "Deafness in patients with otosclerosis usually starts:",
            "options": [
                "at birth",
                "in the first decade of life",
                "in the second-third decade of life",
                "in the third-fourth decade of life",
                "after the fifth decade of life"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3199,
            "question": "Surgical therapy instead of medical therapy of epilepsy is required in:",
            "options": [
                "1%",
                "5%",
                "15 to 20%",
                "25 to 40%",
                "50%"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3200,
            "question": "The best diagnostic test for spinal cord tumor is:",
            "options": [
                "CT scan",
                "electromyography",
                "plain film",
                "MRI",
                "X-ray"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3201,
            "question": "The most frequent indication for lumbar puncture is suspected:",
            "options": ["meningitis", "ruptured Berry aneurysm", "subarachnoid hemorrhage", "head injury", "brain tumor"],
            "answer": "meningitis",
            "answer_index": 0
          },
          {
            "id": 3202,
            "question": "The most common cause of acquired arteriovenous fistula is:",
            "options": ["infection", "blunt trauma", "penetrating injury", "neoplastic invasion", "connective tissue disorder"],
            "answer": "penetrating injury",
            "answer_index": 2
          },
          {
            "id": 3203,
            "question": "Arterial occlusion is differentiated from arterial vasoconstriction by:",
            "options": ["Brodie Trendelenburg test", "Allen test", "Schwartz test", "Adson's test", "Tinel's test"],
            "answer": "Allen test",
            "answer_index": 1
          },
          {
            "id": 3204,
            "question": "Malabsorption of bile salts and vitamin B12 (cobalamin) typically occur after:",
            "options": ["total colectomy", "jejunal resection", "hemorrhoidectomy", "ileal resection", "splenectomy"],
            "answer": "ileal resection",
            "answer_index": 3
          },
          {
            "id": 3205,
            "question": "The most common site of volvulus (twisting of bowel around mesenteric root) is:",
            "options": ["splenic flexure", "cecum", "transverse colon", "sigmoid colon/gastric", "ascending colon"],
            "answer": "sigmoid colon/gastric",
            "answer_index": 3
          },
          {
            "id": 3206,
            "question": "The most common cause of spleen rupture is:",
            "options": ["typhoid fever/malaria", "pregnancy", "infectious mononucleosis", "blunt abdominal trauma", "leukemia/lymphoma"],
            "answer": "blunt abdominal trauma",
            "answer_index": 3
          },
          {
            "id": 3207,
            "question": "Puestow/Du Val procedures are used in surgical treatment of:",
            "options": ["splenic rupture", "chronic pancreatitis", "inguinal hernia", "reflux esophagitis", "carcinoma of the colon"],
            "answer": "chronic pancreatitis",
            "answer_index": 1
          },
          {
            "id": 3208,
            "question": "The most common presenting complaint in patients with carcinoma of the gallbladder is:",
            "options": ["weight loss", "painless jaundice", "palpable mass", "constipation", "intermittent right upper quadrant pain"],
            "answer": "intermittent right upper quadrant pain",
            "answer_index": 4
          },
          {
            "id": 3209,
            "question": "Following are major complications of acute cholecystitis, EXCEPT:",
            "options": ["perforation", "bleeding", "abscess", "fistula", "empyema"],
            "answer": "bleeding",
            "answer_index": 1
          },
          {
            "id": 3210,
            "question": "The most common symptom of gastric carcinoma is:",
            "options": ["melena", "epigastric mass", "dysphagia", "weight loss", "hepatomegaly"],
            "answer": "weight loss",
            "answer_index": 3
          },
          {
            "id": 3211,
            "question": "The most common cause of emphysematous cholecystitis is:",
            "options": ["gram positive bacilli", "aerobic bacilli", "clostridial infections", "enterobacterial infections", "bacteroides"],
            "answer": "clostridial infections",
            "answer_index": 2
          },
          {
            "id": 3212,
            "question": "The most common site of intraperitoneal abscess is:",
            "options": ["subdiaphragmatic", "pelvic", "lower quadrants", "subhepatic", "paracolics"],
            "answer": "lower quadrants",
            "answer_index": 2
          },
          {
            "id": 3213,
            "question": "Perforated duodenal ulcer causes mid epigastric pain which is usually radiated to the:",
            "options": ["back", "shoulders", "right upper quadrant", "left lower quadrant", "right lower quadrant"],
            "answer": "right lower quadrant",
            "answer_index": 4
          },
          {
            "id": 3214,
            "question": "Following are risk factors for carcinoma of esophagus, EXCEPT:",
            "options": ["reflux esophagitis", "esophageal diverticula", "chronic iron deficiency", "congenital esophageal tylosis", "carcinoma of the head/neck"],
            "answer": "esophageal diverticula",
            "answer_index": 1
          },
          {
            "id": 3215,
            "question": "Nissen fundoplication is the most effective surgical procedure in treatment of:",
            "options": ["achalasia", "reflux esophagitis", "hiatal hernia", "esophageal diverticula", "esophageal cancer"],
            "answer": "reflux esophagitis",
            "answer_index": 1
          },
          {
            "id": 3216,
            "question": "The most common heart tumor is:",
            "options": ["myxoma", "fibroma", "lipoma", "teratoma", "sarcoma"],
            "answer": "myxoma",
            "answer_index": 0
          },
          {
            "id": 3217,
            "question": "The most common cause of pericarditis is:",
            "options": ["bacterial contamination", "acute myocardial infarction", "tuberculosis", "rheumatic fever", "unknown (idiopathic)"],
            "answer": "unknown (idiopathic)",
            "answer_index": 4
          },
          {
            "id": 3218,
            "question": "Following are associated with sarcoidosis, EXCEPT:",
            "options": ["positive Kveim test", "hypercalciuria", "hypocalcemia", "erythema nodosum", "leukopenia"],
            "answer": "hypocalcemia",
            "answer_index": 2
          },
          {
            "id": 3219,
            "question": "Spontaneous pneumothorax is most common in:",
            "options": ["infants", "males 50 to 70 years of age", "females 15 to 35 years of age", "males 15 to 35 years of age", "females after menopause"],
            "answer": "males 15 to 35 years of age",
            "answer_index": 3
          },
          {
            "id": 3220,
            "question": "Tietze's syndrome is a painful nonsuppurative inflammation of the:",
            "options": ["pleura", "lung", "intercostal muscle", "mediastinum", "costochondral cartilage"],
            "answer": "costochondral cartilage",
            "answer_index": 4
            },
            {
            "id": 3221,
            "question": "The most common type of thyroiditis is:",
            "options": ["Riedel's thyroiditis (struma)", "acute suppurative thyroiditis", "subacute granulomatous (DeQuervain's) thyroiditis", "Hashimoto's thyroiditis", "none of the above"],
            "answer": "Hashimoto's thyroiditis",
            "answer_index": 3
            },
            {
            "id": 3222,
            "question": "The most common presentation of thyrotoxicosis is:",
            "options": ["diarrhea", "atrial fibrillation", "tachycardia", "weakness", "constipation"],
            "answer": "tachycardia",
            "answer_index": 2
            },
            {
            "id": 3223,
            "question": "The most common malignant tumor of the parotid gland is:",
            "options": ["adenoid cystic carcinoma", "clear cell carcinoma", "mucoepidermoid carcinoma", "adenocarcinoma", "squamous cell carcinoma"],
            "answer": "mucoepidermoid carcinoma",
            "answer_index": 2
            },
            {
            "id": 3224,
            "question": "The most common tumor of the nasal cavity is:",
            "options": ["melanoma", "sarcoma", "adenocarcinoma", "esthesioneuroblastoma", "squamous cell carcinoma"],
            "answer": "squamous cell carcinoma",
            "answer_index": 4
            },
            {
            "id": 3225,
            "question": "Pyomyositis (acute pyogenic infection of muscles) is usually due to:",
            "options": ["klebsiella", "staphylococcus aureus", "escherichia coli", "clostriduim", "bacteroides"],
            "answer": "staphylococcus aureus",
            "answer_index": 1
            },
            {
            "id": 3226,
            "question": "The most common pathogen in surgical wound infection is:",
            "options": ["klebsiella", "staphylococcus aureus", "haemophilus influenzae", "clostriduim", "bacteroides"],
            "answer": "staphylococcus aureus",
            "answer_index": 1
            },
            {
            "id": 3227,
            "question": "The most common cardiac disease is:",
            "options": ["valvular heart disease", "congenital heart disease", "coronary artery disease", "congestive heart failure", "cardiac tumor"],
            "answer": "coronary artery disease",
            "answer_index": 2
            },
            {
            "id": 3228,
            "question": "The most common pulmonary complication in patients who have abdominal surgery is:",
            "options": ["pulmonary embolism", "pneumothorax/pleural effusion", "pulmonary aspiration", "postoperative pneumonia", "atelectasis"],
            "answer": "atelectasis",
            "answer_index": 4
            },
            {
            "id": 3229,
            "question": "The most common pulmonary complication among patients who die after surgery is:",
            "options": ["pulmonary embolism", "pneumothorax/pleural effusion", "pulmonary aspiration", "postoperative pneumonia", "atelectasis"],
            "answer": "postoperative pneumonia",
            "answer_index": 3
            },
            {
            "id": 3230,
            "question": "Which of the following is LEAST likely to be a complication of ileostomy?",
            "options": ["gallstones", "kidney stones", "paraileostomy abscess", "malignant transformation", "diarrhea"],
            "answer": "malignant transformation",
            "answer_index": 3
            },
            {
               "id": 3231,
               "question": "The main complaint in patients with Guillain Barre syndrome (ascending paralysis or acute polyneuropathy) is:",
               "options": ["dyspnea", "weakness", "tachycardia", "abnormalities of sweating", "impaired sphincter control"],
               "answer": "weakness",
               "answer_index": 1
             },
             {
               "id": 3232,
               "question": "Asymptomatic gynecomastia in a 13 year old boy is best managed by:",
               "options": ["mammography", "surgical excision", "reassurance", "chest X ray", "excisional biopsy"],
               "answer": "reassurance",
               "answer_index": 2
             },
             {
               "id": 3233,
               "question": "Diagnosis of paroxysmal nocturnal hemoglobinuria is confirmed by:",
               "options": ["indirect antiglobulin test", "Schilling test", "specific enzyme test", "Ham's (acidified serum) test", "Coomb's test"],
               "answer": "Ham's (acidified serum) test",
               "answer_index": 3
             },
             {
               "id": 3234,
               "question": "Adult polycystic kidney disease is usually discovered:",
               "options": ["at birth", "in the first decade of life", "in the second or third decade of life", "in the fourth or fifth decade of life", "after the sixth decade of life"],
               "answer": "in the fourth or fifth decade of life",
               "answer_index": 3
             },
             {
               "id": 3235,
               "question": "The most common presentation of mumps is:",
               "options": ["high fever", "abdominal pain", "nausea/vomiting", "scrotal swelling", "parotid swelling"],
               "answer": "parotid swelling",
               "answer_index": 4
             },
             {
               "id": 3236,
               "question": "Botulism is characterized by:",
               "options": ["hepatosplenomegaly", "fever", "rash", "diplopia", "hypercalcemia"],
               "answer": "diplopia",
               "answer_index": 3
             },
             {
               "id": 3237,
               "question": "Symptoms of pyridoxine (B6) deficiency are similar to those seen with the deficiency of:",
               "options": ["cyanocobalamin (B12)", "ascorbic acid", "niacin", "riboflavin (B2)", "thiamine (B1)"],
               "answer": "cyanocobalamin (B12)",
               "answer_index": 0
             },
             {
               "id": 3238,
               "question": "The drug of choice for symptomatic patients with toxoplasmosis (caused by protozoon) is:",
               "options": ["corticosteroids", "clindamycin", "pyrimethamine/sulfadiazine", "trimethoprim sulphamethoxazole", "tetracycline"],
               "answer": "pyrimethamine/sulfadiazine",
               "answer_index": 2
             },
             {
               "id": 3239,
               "question": "Toxoplasmosis is caused by:",
               "options": ["virus", "parasite", "protozoa", "spirochete", "rickettsia"],
               "answer": "protozoa",
               "answer_index": 2
             },
             {
               "id": 3240,
               "question": "Courvoisier's law (palpable gallbladder and jaundice) and Trousseau's sign (migratory thrombophlebitis) are associated with:",
               "options": ["splenic rupture", "hepatoma", "peptic ulcer", "gastric cancer", "pancreatic cancer"],
               "answer": "pancreatic cancer",
               "answer_index": 4
             },
             {
               "id": 3241,
               "question": "Following are criteria for the diagnosis of systemic lupus erythematosus, EXCEPT:",
               "options": ["malar rash", "photosensitivity", "leukocytosis", "serositis", "thrombocytopenia"],
               "answer": "leukocytosis",
               "answer_index": 2
             },
             {
               "id": 3242,
               "question": "Systemic lupus erythematosus is LEAST likely to be associated with:",
               "options": ["hepatitis", "synovitis", "myocarditis", "conjunctivitis", "pleurisy (pleuritis)"],
               "answer": "hepatitis",
               "answer_index": 0
             },
             {
               "id": 3243,
               "question": "The sulfonamides are contraindicated in the latter part of pregnancy because of the risk of neonatal:",
               "options": ["hemorrhage", "blindness", "deafness", "teeth discoloration", "kernicterus"],
               "answer": "kernicterus",
               "answer_index": 4
             },
             {
               "id": 3244,
               "question": "The most common cause of cirrhosis of the liver in North America is:",
               "options": ["hemochromatosis", "alcoholic hepatitis", "drug induced hepatitis", "viral hepatitis", "primary biliary cirrhosis"],
               "answer": "alcoholic hepatitis",
               "answer_index": 1
             },
             {
               "id": 3245,
               "question": "Congenital intracranial aneurysms:",
               "options": ["are usually symptomatic", "are more common in children than in adults", "usually occur at arterial biforcations", "are never multiple", "cause epidural hemorrhage when rupture"],
               "answer": "usually occur at arterial biforcations",
               "answer_index": 2
             },
             {
               "id": 3246,
               "question": "The most reliable test for diagnosis of transient ischemic attacks is:",
               "options": ["bilateral carotid arteriography", "CT scan of the head", "ultrasound", "X ray of the head", "electroencephalogram"],
               "answer": "bilateral carotid arteriography",
               "answer_index": 0
             },
             {
               "id": 3247,
               "question": "Drop attacks (atonic seizures, falls without warning/without loss of consciousness) are associated with:",
               "options": ["epileptic seizure", "migraine headache", "pseudotumor cerebri", "subarachnoid hemorrhage (saccular aneurysms)", "transient ischemic attacks (vertebrobasilar ischemia)"],
               "answer": "transient ischemic attacks (vertebrobasilar ischemia)",  
               "answer_index": 4
             },
             {
               "id": 3248,
               "question": "Following are features of cholera, EXCEPT:",
               "options": ["severe (rice-water) diarrhea", "marked dehydration", "metabolic alkalosis", "marked hemoconcentration", "hypotension/hypokalemia"],
               "answer": "metabolic alkalosis",
               "answer_index": 2
             },
             {
               "id": 3249,
               "question": "Nearly all patients who receive a full course of radiation therapy for cancer of the lung/breast develop:",
               "options": ["leukemia", "hepatitis", "skin ulcers", "polycythemia", "pulmonary fibrosis"],
               "answer": "pulmonary fibrosis",
               "answer_index": 4
             },
             {
               "id": 3250,
               "question": "Allergic bronchopulmonary aspergillosis is best treated with:",
               "options": ["bronchodilators", "anticholinergics", "antimediators", "corticosteroids/prednisone", "theophyllines/amphotericin B"],
               "answer": "corticosteroids/prednisone",
               "answer_index": 3
             },
             {
               "id": 3251,
               "question": "Cystic fibrosis is LEAST likely to be associated with:",
               "options": ["digital clubbing", "abnormal xylose absorption", "glomerulonephritis", "nasal polyps", "gallstones/biliary cirrhosis"],
               "answer": "glomerulonephritis",
               "answer_index": 2
             },
             {
               "id": 3252,
               "question": "Intrauterine device (IUD) has a failure rate of 2%-3%. absolute contraindication/s of (IUD) is/are:",
               "options": ["multiple sexual partners", "pregnancy/pelvic inflammatory disease", "diabetes mellitus/history of ectopic pregnancy", "severe dysmenorrhea/endometrial hyperplasia", "valvular heart disease"],
               "answer": "pregnancy/pelvic inflammatory disease",
               "answer_index": 1
             },
             {
               "id": 3253,
               "question": "The typical site of herpes zoster (shingles) is:",
               "options": ["lower extremities", "face/hands", "intertriginous areas", "lower abdomen", "distribution of a nerve root"],
               "answer": "distribution of a nerve root",
               "answer_index": 4
             },
             {
               "id": 3254,
               "question": "The average incubation period in varicella (chickenpox) is:",
               "options": ["4 days", "9 days", "14 days", "20 days", "one month"],
               "answer": "14 days",
               "answer_index": 2
             },
             {
               "id": 3255,
               "question": "Stein Leventhal syndrome (polycystic ovary syndrome) is characterized by amenorrhea/hirsutism/obesity and:",
               "options": ["low estrogen levels", "high serum FSH", "high serum LH", "low urinary 17 ketosteroids", "low plasma testosterone"],
               "answer": "high serum LH",
               "answer_index": 2
             },
             {
               "id": 3256,
               "question": "Sheehan's syndrome is associated with pituitary:",
               "options": ["trauma", "adenoma", "fibrosis", "hyperplasia", "hemorrhagic necrosis"],
               "answer": "hemorrhagic necrosis",
               "answer_index": 4
             },
             {
               "id": 3257,
               "question": "The most important test for the diagnosis of adrenogenital syndrome is:",
               "options": ["plasma cortisol", "urinary 17 ketosteroid", "urinary gonadotropines", "serum LH", "dexamethasone suppression test"],
               "answer": "urinary 17 ketosteroid",
               "answer_index": 1
             },
             {
               "id": 3258,
               "question": "The most common malignant bone tumor after 60 years of age is:",
               "options": ["osteogenic sarcoma", "Ewing's tumor", "primary chondrosarcoma", "multiple myeloma", "fibrosarcoma"],
               "answer": "multiple myeloma",
               "answer_index": 3
             },
             {
               "id": 3259,
               "question": "The most common cause of hypoparathyroidism is:",
               "options": ["idiopathic", "inflammatory", "thyroidectomy", "neoplastic", "congenital"],
               "answer": "thyroidectomy",
               "answer_index": 2
             },
             {
               "id": 3260,
               "question": "The most common site of osteogenic sarcoma (osteosarcoma) is:",
               "options": ["distal metaphysis of the humerus", "proximal metaphysis of the humerus", "proximal metaphysis of the ulna", "distal metaphysis of the femur", "diaphysis of the humerus"],
               "answer": "distal metaphysis of the femur",
               "answer_index": 3
             },
             {
               "id": 3261,
               "question": "Which of the following is caused by human herpes virus type 6 and 7?",
               "options": ["roseola", "measles", "rubella", "infectious mononucleosis", "erythema infectiosum (fifth disease)"],
               "answer": "roseola",
               "answer_index": 0
             },
             {
               "id": 3262,
               "question": "Which of the following is caused by human parvovirus B19?",
               "options": ["roseola", "measles", "rubella", "infectious mononucleosis", "erythema infectiosum (fifth disease)"],
               "answer": "erythema infectiosum (fifth disease)",
               "answer_index": 4
             },
             {
               "id": 3263,
               "question": "Which of the following is caused by paramyxovirus?",
               "options": ["roseola", "measles", "rubella", "infectious mononucleosis", "erythema infectiosum (fifth disease)"],
               "answer": "measles",
               "answer_index": 1
             },
             {
               "id": 3264,
               "question": "In North America, AIDS is most common among:",
               "options": ["hemophiliacs", "heterosexual individuals", "homosexual or bisexual men", "homosexual intravenous drug users", "homosexual or bisexual intravenous drug users"],
               "answer": "homosexual or bisexual men",
               "answer_index": 2
             },
             {
               "id": 3265,
               "question": "In ages less than 50 years, arcus senilis indicates:",
               "options": ["hyperammonemia", "hyperprolactinoma", "hyperaldosteronism", "hyperparathyroidism", "hypercholesterolemia"],
               "answer": "hypercholesterolemia",
               "answer_index": 4
             },
             {
               "id": 3266,
               "question": "Which of the following types of glaucoma is the most common?",
               "options": ["congenital glaucoma", "normal pressure glaucoma", "chronic open angle glaucoma", "acute angle closure glaucoma", "chronic angle closure glaucoma"],
               "answer": "chronic open angle glaucoma",
               "answer_index": 2
             },
             {
               "id": 3267,
               "question": "Following are characteristics of SIADH, EXCEPT:",
               "options": ["salt wasting", "hyponatremia", "concentrated urine", "high plasma osmolarity", "high urinary osmolarity"],
               "answer": "high plasma osmolarity",
               "answer_index": 3
             },
             {
               "id": 3268,
               "question": "Tzanck smear or cells (multinucleated giant cells) are seen in 75% of cases of:",
               "options": ["impetigo", "tularemia", "gonorrhea", "erythrasma", "genital herpes"],
               "answer": "genital herpes",
               "answer_index": 4
             },
             {
               "id": 3269,
               "question": "Renal secretion of potassium is decreased by:",
               "options": ["alkalosis", "aldosterone", "spironolactone", "hyperparathyroidism", "diet high in potassium"],
               "answer": "spironolactone",
               "answer_index": 2
             },
             {
               "id": 3270,
               "question": "Sever skeletomuscular pain is characteristic of:",
               "options": ["malaria", "dengue fever", "yellow fever", "typhoid fever", "none of the above"],
               "answer": "dengue fever",
               "answer_index": 1
             },
             {
               "id": 3271,
               "question": "Metabolic alkalosis is caused by:",
               "options": ["diarrhea", "hyperaldosteronism", "adrenal insufficiency", "chronic renal failure", "methanol (methyl alcohol) poisoning"],
               "answer": "hyperaldosteronism",
               "answer_index": 1
             },
             {
               "id": 3272,
               "question": "Respiratory acidosis is most compatible with:",
               "options": ["pH = 7.41, HCO3 = 30, Pco2 = 42", "pH = 7.42, HCO3 = 42, Pco2 = 40", "pH = 7.31, HCO3 = 28, Pco2 = 62", "pH = 7.48, HCO3 = 16, Pco2 = 18", "pH = 7.67, HCO3 = 46, Pco2 = 48"],
               "answer": "pH = 7.31, HCO3 = 28, Pco2 = 62",
               "answer_index": 2
             },
             {
               "id": 3273,
               "question": "Berger's disease (IgA nephropathy) is associated with primary glomerulonephritis type:",
               "options": ["membranous", "minimal changes", "non-proliferative", "mesangial proliferative", "focal segmental sclerosis"],
               "answer": "mesangial proliferative",
               "answer_index": 3
             },
             {
               "id": 3274,
               "question": "Which of the following ECG changes is typical of hypokalemia?",
               "options": ["widening QRS", "tall T waves", "prominent U waves", "prolonged PR intervals", "all of the above"],
               "answer": "prominent U waves",
               "answer_index": 2
             },
             {
               "id": 3275,
               "question": "During pregnancy:",
               "options": ["RBF is decreased", "GFR is decreased", "kidney size is decreased", "serum creatinine and urea are decreased", "renal pelvis and ureters are constricted"],
               "answer": "serum creatinine and urea are decreased",
               "answer_index": 3
             },
             {
               "id": 3276,
               "question": "A patient with leukemia develops pneumonia, which of the following is most likely to be the cause?",
               "answer": "cytomegalovirus",
               "answer_index": 3
             },
             {
               "id": 3277,
               "question": "An AIDS patient with decreased vision develops hemiparesis and then quadriparesis, the most likely diagnosis is:",
               "options": ["poliomyelitis", "multiple sclerosis", "Creutzfeldt Jakob disease", "subacute sclerosing panencephalitis (SSP)", "progressive multifocal leukoencephalitis (PML)"],
               "answer": "progressive multifocal leukoencephalitis (PML)",
               "answer_index": 4
             },
             {
               "id": 3278,
               "question": "The most common cause of anaerobic infection in humans is:",
               "options": ["bacteroides", "fusobacterium", "anaerobic cocci", "clostridium difficile", "clostridium perfringens"],
               "answer": "bacteroides",
               "answer_index": 0
             },
             {
               "id": 3279,
               "question": "Abdominal cramps is LEAST likely to be caused by:",
               "options": ["vibrio cholerae", "bacillus cereus", "escherichia coli", "staphylococcus aureus", "clostridium perfringens"],
               "answer": "vibrio cholerae",
               "answer_index": 0
             },
             {
               "id": 3280,
               "question": "Following are symptoms of acute viral hepatitis, EXCEPT:",
               "options": ["rash", "fever", "jaundice", "dark urine", "dark stools"],
               "answer": "dark stools",
               "answer_index": 4
             },
             {
               "id": 3281,
               "question": "The most common form of acute hepatitis in children in hepatitis:",
               "options": ["A", "B", "C", "D", "E"],
               "answer": "A",
               "answer_index": 0
             },
             {
               "id": 3282,
               "question": "Cigarette smoking causes anal cancer and:",
               "options": ["macrosomy", "renal cancer", "thyroid cancer", "chronic hepatitis", "all of the above"],
               "answer": "renal cancer",
               "answer_index": 1
             },
             {
               "id": 3283,
               "question": "ECG shows large R waves with ST-segment depression in leads V1 and V2, the most likely diagnosis is:",
               "options": ["LBBB", "hyperkalemia", "inferior infarct", "posterior infarct", "pericardial effusion"],
               "answer": "posterior infarct",
               "answer_index": 3
             },
             {
               "id": 3284,
               "question": "Arterial blood values show pH = 7.42, Pco2 = 42 and HCO3 = 24, the most likely diagnosis is:",
               "options": ["normal status", "metabolic acidosis", "metabolic alkalosis", "respiratory acidosis", "respiratory alkalosis"],
               "answer": "normal status",
               "answer_index": 0
             },
             {
               "id": 3285,
               "question": "The safest tetracycline given to patients with renal failure is:",
               "options": ["minocycline", "doxycycline", "methacycline", "demeclocycline", "oxytetracycline"],
               "answer": "doxycycline",
               "answer_index": 1
             },
             {
               "id": 3286,
               "question": "Auer rod (an eosinophilic needlelike blast cell) is pathognomonic of:",
               "options": ["acute lymphoblastic leukemia", "acute myeloid (myeogenous) leukemia", "chronic myelocytic leukemia", "hairy cell leukemia", "Hodgkin's lymphoma"],
               "answer": "acute myeloid (myeogenous) leukemia",
               "answer_index": 1
             },
             {
               "id": 3287,
               "question": "The most common cause of sepsis (septicemia) and death in burn patients is:",
               "options": ["klebsiella pneumoniae", "pseudomonas aeruginosa", "escherichia coli", "borrelia burgdorferi", "haemophilus influenzae"],
               "answer": "pseudomonas aeruginosa",
               "answer_index": 1
             },
             {
               "id": 3288,
               "question": "The causative agent in bubonic plague (transmitted by flea bite/treated with streptomycin) is:",
               "options": ["bacterial", "viral", "chlamydial", "protozoal", "unknown"],
               "answer": "bacterial",
               "answer_index": 0
             },
             {
               "id": 3289,
               "question": "The causative agent in Kawasaki's disease is:",
               "options": ["bacterial", "viral", "chlamydial", "protozoal", "unknown"],
               "answer": "unknown",
               "answer_index": 4
             },
             {
               "id": 3290,
               "question": "Bubonic plague is caused by:",
               "options": ["yersinia pestis (aerobic gram-negative rod)", "haemophilus ducreyi", "borrelia recurrentis", "borrelia burgdorferi", "rickettsia prowazekii"],
               "answer": "yersinia pestis (aerobic gram-negative rod)",
               "answer_index": 0
             },
             {
               "id": 3291,
               "question": "Epidemic louse-borne typhus (classical typhus fever) is caused by:",
               "options": ["donovania granulomatis", "haemophilus ducreyi", "borrelia recurrentis", "borrelia burgdorferi", "rickettsia prowazekii"],
               "answer": "rickettsia prowazekii",
               "answer_index": 4
             },
             {
               "id": 3292,
               "question": "Relapsing fever is caused by:",
               "options": ["donovania granulomatis", "haemophilus ducreyi", "borrelia recurrentis", "borrelia burgdorferi", "haemophilus influenzae"],
               "answer": "borrelia recurrentis",
               "answer_index": 2
             },
             {
               "id": 3293,
               "question": "Strawberry spots on the vaginal mucosa are most likely to be seen in:",
               "options": ["syphilis", "gonorrhea", "candidiasis", "trichomoniasis", "granuloma inguinale"],
               "answer": "trichomoniasis",
               "answer_index": 3
             },
             {
               "id": 3294,
               "question": "Raspberry or strawberry tongue is associated with:",
               "options": ["trichomoniasis", "measles", "mumps", "scarlet fever", "infective endocarditis"],
               "answer": "scarlet fever",
               "answer_index": 3
             },
             {
               "id": 3295,
               "question": "Starvation decreases glucose and insulin, increases glucagone and ketone body in the blood and causes:",
               "options": ["hypochromic microcytic anemia", "hypochromic normocytic anemia", "hyperchromic macrocytic anemia", "hemolysis", "none of the above"],
               "answer": "hypochromic normocytic anemia",
               "answer_index": 1
             },
             {
               "id": 3296,
               "question": "Self mutilation/hyperuricemia are associated with:",
               "options": ["Wilson's disease", "Turner's syndrome", "Fabry's disease", "Lesch Nyhan syndrome", "Von Hippel Lindau disease"],
               "answer": "Lesch Nyhan syndrome",
               "answer_index": 3
             },
             {
               "id": 3297,
               "question": "Progressive renal failure is most likely to occur in:",
               "options": ["Wilson's disease", "Turner's syndrome", "Fabry's disease", "Lesch Nyhan syndrome", "Von Hippel Lindau disease"],
               "answer": "Fabry's disease",
               "answer_index": 2
             },
             {
               "id": 3298,
               "question": "A karyotype of 46XX is often seen in:",
               "options": ["Down's syndrome", "Klinefelter's syndrome", "Turner's syndrome", "testicular feminization", "true hermaphroditism"],
               "answer": "true hermaphroditism",
               "answer_index": 4
             },
             {
               "id": 3299,
               "question": "A karyotype of 46XY is associated with:",
               "options": ["Down's syndrome", "Klinefelter's syndrome", "Turner's syndrome", "testicular feminization", "true hermaphroditism"],
               "answer": "testicular feminization",
               "answer_index": 3
             },
             {
               "id": 3300,
               "question": "Following are associated with mental retardation (IQ below 70), EXCEPT:",
               "options": ["congenital hypothyroidism", "homocystinuria", "McArdle's disease", "retinoblastoma", "Tay Sachs disease"],
               "answer": "McArdle's disease",
               "answer_index": 2
             },
             {
               "id": 3301,
               "question": "Following are associated with mental retardation, EXCEPT:",
               "options": ["neurofibromatosis", "homocystinuria", "Niemann Pick disease", "galactosemia", "Tay Sachs disease"],
               "answer": "neurofibromatosis",
               "answer_index": 0
             },
             {
               "id": 3302,
               "question": "Death from systemic lupus erythematosus is usually due to:",
               "options": ["pneumonia", "cardiac failure", "asphyxia", "renal failure", "sepsis"],
               "answer": "renal failure",
               "answer_index": 3
             },
             {
               "id": 3303,
               "question": "Absolute contraindication to combined birth control pill include:",
               "options": ["hypertension", "diabetes mellitus", "migraine headache", "history of hepatic tumor", "active gallbladder disease"],
               "answer": "history of hepatic tumor",
               "answer_index": 3
             },
             {
               "id": 3304,
               "question": "Mittelschmerz is the pain caused by:",
               "options": ["pericardial effusion", "pleural effusion", "ectopic pregnancy", "ovarian torsion", "ruptured follicular cyst at the time of ovulation"],
               "answer": "ruptured follicular cyst at the time of ovulation",
               "answer_index": 4
             },
             {
               "id": 3305,
               "question": "Blepharitis is particularly common in children with:",
               "options": ["necrotizing enterocolitis", "maple syrup urine disease", "phenylketonuria", "Down's syndrome", "coarctation of the aorta"],
               "answer": "Down's syndrome",
               "answer_index": 3
             },
             {
               "id": 3306,
               "question": "Characteristic (E shape) of esophagus on barium swallow is seen in:",
               "options": ["patent ductus arteriosus", "coarctation of the aorta", "mitral valve prolapse", "aortic stenosis", "atrial septal defect"],
               "answer": "coarctation of the aorta",
               "answer_index": 1
             },
             {
               "id": 3307,
               "question": "Continuous machinery murmur is heard in:",
               "options": ["patent ductus arteriosus", "Ebstein's anomaly", "mitral valve prolapse", "aortic stenosis", "atrial septal defect"],
               "answer": "patent ductus arteriosus",
               "answer_index": 0
             },
             {
               "id": 3308,
               "question": "Osteogenic sarcoma/Ewing's sarcoma of the bone most frequently present:",
               "options": ["painful bone mass", "no symptoms", "headache", "paraplegia", "painless bone mass"],
               "answer": "painful bone mass",
               "answer_index": 0
             },
             {
               "id": 3309,
               "question": "Periosteal elevation/lytic destruction/(onion skin or onion peel) appearance on bone X ray are seen in:",
               "options": ["multiple myeloma", "osteogenic sarcoma", "Ewing's sarcoma", "osteomyelitis", "eosinophilic granuloma of bone"],
               "answer": "Ewing's sarcoma",
               "answer_index": 2
             },
             {
               "id": 3310,
               "question": "The most common brain tumor in children is:",
               "options": ["astrocytoma", "medulloblastoma", "glioblastoma multiforme", "craniopharyngioma", "oligodendroglioma"],
               "answer": "astrocytoma",
               "answer_index": 0
            },
            {
               "id": 3311,
               "question": "Children with neuroblastoma (the most common congenital tumor occurring during the first year of life) usually present:",
               "options": ["maculopapular rash", "polyuria", "constipation", "nausea/vomiting", "palpable abdominal mass"],
               "answer": "palpable abdominal mass",
               "answer_index": 4
             },
             {
               "id": 3312,
               "question": "Histoplasmosis is best treated with:",
               "options": ["metronidazole", "vancomycin", "amphotericin B", "griseofulvin", "streptomycin"],
               "answer": "amphotericin B",
               "answer_index": 2
             },
             {
               "id": 3313,
               "question": "Schistosomiasis is best treated with:",
               "options": ["furazolidone", "praziquantel", "metronidazole", "pyrimethamine", "mebendazole"],
               "answer": "praziquantel",
               "answer_index": 1
             },
             {
               "id": 3314,
               "question": "The most common presentation of acquired toxoplasmosis is:",
               "options": ["cervical adenopathy", "maculopapular rash", "fever", "splenomegaly", "chorioretinitis"],
               "answer": "cervical adenopathy",
               "answer_index": 0
             },
             {
               "id": 3315,
               "question": "The most characteristic feature of Lyme disease is:",
               "options": ["fever/chills", "headache/myalgia", "Bell's palsy", "arthritis", "erythema migrans"],
               "answer": "erythema migrans",
               "answer_index": 4
             },
             {
               "id": 3316,
               "question": "Weil's disease (icterohemorrhagic fever) is characterized by jaundice and high mortality rate which is a severe form of:",
               "options": ["tularemia", "listeriosis", "psittacosis", "leptospirosis", "relapsing fever"],
               "answer": "leptospirosis",
               "answer_index": 3
             },
             {
               "id": 3317,
               "question": "Relapsing fever (borreliosis) is usually diagnosed by:",
               "options": ["blood culture", "muscle biopsy", "lymph node biopsy", "microscopic examination of the blood", "microscopic examination of the urine"],
               "answer": "microscopic examination of the blood",
               "answer_index": 3
             },
             {
               "id": 3318,
               "question": "Chlamydia psittaci (psittacosis) is transmitted to humans mainly by:",
               "options": ["humans", "cows", "birds", "raccoons", "skunks"],
               "answer": "birds",
               "answer_index": 2
             },
             {
               "id": 3319,
               "question": "Classic (snowstorm) appearance on chest X ray is seen in:",
               "options": ["mycoplasmal pneumonia", "sarcoidosis", "legionella infection", "miliary tuberculosis", "bronchial asthma"],
               "answer": "miliary tuberculosis",
               "answer_index": 3
             },
             {
               "id": 3320,
               "question": "The most common cause of acute purulent otitis media is:",
               "options": ["staphylococcus epidermatidis", "escherichia coli", "staphylococcus aureus", "streptococcus (pneumococcus) pneumonia", "haemophilus influenzae type B"],
               "answer": "streptococcus (pneumococcus) pneumonia",
               "answer_index": 3
             },
             {
               "id": 3321,
               "question": "Group B streptococcal disease (which is most common in infants) is best treated with:",
               "options": ["penicillin G", "amphotericin B", "ampicillin", "erythromycin", "corticosteroids"],
               "answer": "penicillin G",
               "answer_index": 0
             },
             {
               "id": 3322,
               "question": "Which of the following is the most common cause of septic arthritis in childern less than 2 years:",
               "options": ["salmonella", "escherichia coli", "neisseria gonorrheae", "staphylococcus aureus", "pseudomonas aeruginosa"],
               "answer": "escherichia coli",
               "answer_index": 1
             },
             {
               "id": 3323,
               "question": "Cholera is best prevented by:",
               "options": ["amoxicillin", "ampicillin", "streptomycin", "kanamycin", "vancomycin"],
               "answer": "streptomycin",
               "answer_index": 2
             },
             {
               "id": 3324,
               "question": "Shigellosis (bacillary dysentery) is best treated with:",
               "options": ["amoxicillin", "trimethoprim sulphamethoxazole", "streptomycin", "kanamycin", "vancomycin"],
               "answer": "trimethoprim sulphamethoxazole",
               "answer_index": 1
             },
             {
               "id": 3325,
               "question": "The most common cause of abnormal uterine bleeding is:",
               "options": ["trauma", "tumor", "infection", "coagulopathy", "dysfunctional uterine bleeding"],
               "answer": "dysfunctional uterine bleeding",
               "answer_index": 4
             },
             {
               "id": 3326,
               "question": "The usual site of ganglion is:",
               "options": ["ankle", "elbow", "vertebral spine", "finger", "wrist"],
               "answer": "wrist",
               "answer_index": 4
             },
             {
               "id": 3327,
               "question": "The lesion in Legg-Calve-Perthes disease (coxa plana) is located in:",
               "options": ["tibial tubercle", "calcaneus", "vertebral ring", "femoral head", "tarsal navicular"],
               "answer": "femoral head",
               "answer_index": 3
             },
             {
               "id": 3328,
               "question": "Volkmann's ischemic contracture (compartment syndrome) is associated with:",
               "options": ["fracture of the hip", "fracture of the femoral head", "fracture of the patella", "fracture of the clavicle", "supracondylar fracture of the humerus"],
               "answer": "supracondylar fracture of the humerus",
               "answer_index": 4
             },
             {
               "id": 3329,
               "question": "Air in bowel wall and/or in biliary tree is seen in:",
               "options": ["Meckel's diverticulum", "necrotizing enterocolitis", "drug induced colitis", "Hirschsprung's disease", "ulcerative colitis"],
               "answer": "necrotizing enterocolitis",
               "answer_index": 1
             },
             {
               "id": 3330,
               "question": "Meckel's diverticulum (usually presents as painless rectal bleeding/best treated with excision)is best diagnosed by:",
               "options": ["abdominal X ray", "ultrasound", "99mTc scan", "stool examination", "intestinal biopsy"],
               "answer": "99mTc scan",
               "answer_index": 2
             },
             {
               "id": 3331,
               "question": "Congenital fusion of the cervical vertebrae is seen in:",
               "options": ["osteoporosis", "Tay Sachs disease", "Marfan syndrome", "Prader Willi syndrome", "Klippel Feil syndrome"],
               "answer": "Klippel Feil syndrome",
               "answer_index": 4
             },
             {
               "id": 3332,
               "question": "Long fingers/toes (arachnodactyly) is associated with:",
               "options": ["myasthenia gravis", "Tay Sachs disease", "Marfan syndrome", "Prader Willi syndrome", "Down syndrome"],
               "answer": "Marfan syndrome",
               "answer_index": 2
             },
             {
               "id": 3333,
               "question": "Primary brain tumors in children most commonly are:",
               "options": ["craniopharyngiomas", "germ cell tumors", "glial cell tumors", "meningeal tumors", "lymphomas"],
               "answer": "glial cell tumors",
               "answer_index": 2
             },
             {
               "id": 3334,
               "question": "The hallmark of early renal failure is:",
               "options": ["hypertension", "oliguria", "uremia", "hypercreatininemia", "hyperkalemia"],
               "answer": "oliguria",
               "answer_index": 1
             },
             {
               "id": 3335,
               "question": "Chlamydial pneumonia with conjunctivitis and cough, occurs most commonly in ages:",
               "options": ["2 to 12 weeks", "1 to 2 years", "4 to 6 years", "6 to 10 years", "12 to 14 years"],
               "answer": "2 to 12 weeks",
               "answer_index": 0
             },
             {
               "id": 3336,
               "question": "Fever is LEAST likely to be associated with:",
               "options": ["bacterial pneumonia", "viral pneumonia", "mycoplasmal pneumonia", "chlamydial pneumonia", "aspiration pneumonia"],
               "answer": "aspiration pneumonia",
               "answer_index": 3
             },
             {
               "id": 3337,
               "question": "Mediastinitis is usually due to a complication of:",
               "options": ["radiotherapy", "lung cancer", "chylothorax", "esophageal carcinoma", "iatrogenic esophageal perforation"],
               "answer": "iatrogenic esophageal perforation",
               "answer_index": 4
             },
             {
               "id": 3338,
               "question": "Which of the following is/are LEAST likely to cause bloody diarrhea?",
               "options": ["shigella/escherichia coli", "cryptosporidium/yersinia", "clostridium perfringens", "clostridium difficile/campylobacter", "salmonella/vibrio parahaemolyticus"],
               "answer": "clostridium perfringens",
               "answer_index": 2
             },
             {
               "id": 3339,
               "question": "Following are associated with blood in stool, EXCEPT:",
               "options": ["giardia lamblia", "cryptosporidium", "shigella", "clostridium difficile", "salmonella"],
               "answer": "giardia lamblia",
               "answer_index": 0
             },
             {
               "id": 3340,
               "question": "The most common small bowel cancer in children is:",
               "options": ["adenocarcinoma", "squamous cell carcinoma", "lymphosarcoma", "leiomyosarcoma", "none of the above"],
               "answer": "lymphosarcoma",
               "answer_index": 2
             },
             {
               "id": 3341,
               "question": "Olive sized mass in the subphrenic location is usually felt in:",
               "options": ["intussusception", "hiatal hernia", "pyloric stenosis", "Meckel's diverticulum", "congenital megacolon"],
               "answer": "pyloric stenosis",
               "answer_index": 2
             },
             {
               "id": 3342,
               "question": "The most common cause of intestinal obstruction in the first 2 years of life is:",
               "options": ["foreign body", "intestinal lymphoma", "pyloric stenosis", "Meckel's diverticulum", "intussusception"],
               "answer": "intussusception",
               "answer_index": 4
             },
             {
               "id": 3343,
               "question": "2 year old child with a sausage shaped mass in upper abdomen and blood-stained stools, the most likely diagnosis is:",
               "options": ["intussusception", "hiatal hernia", "pyloric stenosis", "Meckel's diverticulum", "congenital megacolon"],
               "answer": "intussusception",
               "answer_index": 0
             },
             {
               "id": 3344,
               "question": "(String sign) on X ray is associated with:",
               "options": ["hiatal hernia", "congenital megacolon", "Meckel's diverticulum", "peptic ulcer/ulcerative colitis", "pyloric stenosis/Crohn's colitis"],
               "answer": "pyloric stenosis/Crohn's colitis",
               "answer_index": 4  
             },
             {
               "id": 3345,
               "question": "The most common pathogen in myocarditis/ pericarditis is:",
               "options": ["mumps virus", "cytomegalovirus", "herpes virus", "coxackievirus A", "coxackievirus B"],
               "answer": "coxackievirus B",
               "answer_index": 4
             },
             {
               "id": 3346,
               "question": "The most common cyanotic congenital heart defect presenting after 2 weeks of age is:",
               "options": ["hypoplastic left heart syndrome", "tricuspid atresia", "pulmonary atresia", "Tetralogy of Fallot", "transposition of the great arteries"],
               "answer": "Tetralogy of Fallot",
               "answer_index": 3
             },
             {
               "id": 3347,
               "question": "Midsystolic click followed by late or midsystolic murmur is heard in:",
               "options": ["patent ductus arteriosus", "ventricular septal defect", "atrial septal defect", "mitral valve prolapse", "coarctation of the aorta"],
               "answer": "mitral valve prolapse",
               "answer_index": 3
             },
             {
               "id": 3348,
               "question": "Among congenital heart diseases, the incidence of ventricular septal defect is about:",
               "options": ["5%", "10%", "25%", "45%", "50%"],
               "answer": "25%",
               "answer_index": 2
             },
             {
               "id": 3349,
               "question": "The most common cause of congestive heart failure in children is:",
               "options": ["rheumatic fever", "respiratory disease", "sepsis/acidosis", "myocarditis", "congenital heart disease"],
               "answer": "congenital heart disease",
               "answer_index": 4
             },
             {
               "id": 3350,
               "question": "The most common anterior mediastinal mass in infants is:",
               "options": ["thymoma", "lymphoma", "thymic cyst", "normal thymus", "teratoma"],
               "answer": "normal thymus",
               "answer_index": 3
             },
             {
               "id": 3351,
               "question": "The most common cause of rapidly developing mediastinal compression in children is:",
               "options": ["thymoma", "lymphosarcoma", "bronchogenic cyst", "neuroblastoma", "neuroganglioblastoma"],
               "answer": "neuroblastoma",
               "answer_index": 3
             },
             {
               "id": 3352,
               "question": "The most common solid malignant tumor in children under the age of 4 years is:",
               "options": ["Wilm's tumor (nephroblastoma)", "lymphosarcoma", "adenocarcinoma of pancreas", "neuroblastoma", "hepatoma"],
               "answer": "neuroblastoma",
               "answer_index": 3
             },
             {
               "id": 3353,
               "question": "The most common cause of acute hospital admission in children less than 2 years of age is:",
               "options": ["viral croup", "bronchitis", "bronchiolitis", "laryngomalacia", "epiglottitis"],
               "answer": "bronchiolitis",
               "answer_index": 2
             },
             {
               "id": 3354,
               "question": "Which of the following is LEAST likely to be seen in chlamydial pneumonia:",
               "options": ["fever", "wheezes", "cough", "conjunctivitis", "nasal discharge"],
               "answer": "conjunctivitis",
               "answer_index": 3
             },
             {
               "id": 3355,
               "question": "Diagnosis of laryngomalacia (congenital laryngeal stridor) is established by:",
               "options": ["laryngeal biopsy", "laryngoscopy/X-ray", "pulmonary function tests", "chest X-ray", "arterial blood gases"],
               "answer": "laryngoscopy/X-ray",
               "answer_index": 1
             },
             {
               "id": 3356,
               "question": "Following are features of viral croup, EXCEPT:",
               "options": ["stridor", "barking cough", "epiglottid enlargement", "absence of fever in most cases", "subepiglottid narrowing (steeple sign)"],
               "answer": "epiglottid enlargement",
               "answer_index": 2
             },
             {
               "id": 3357,
               "question": "Diagnosis of infectious mononucleosis is confirmed by:",
               "options": ["urinalysis", "monospot test", "sputum culture", "chest X ray", "lymph node biopsy"],
               "answer": "monospot test",
               "answer_index": 1
             },
             {
               "id": 3358,
               "question": "Tiny ulcers on the anterior palate of the oral cavity are most likely due to:",
               "options": ["infectious mononucleosis", "measles", "oral thrush", "herpangina", "oral syphilis"],
               "answer": "herpangina",
               "answer_index": 3
             },
             {
               "id": 3359,
               "question": "The most common cause of tonsillar abscess is:",
               "options": ["staphylococcus aureus", "beta hemolytic streptococci", "alpha hemolytic streptococci", "escherichia coli", "bacterioides fragilis"],
               "answer": "staphylococcus aureus",
               "answer_index": 0
             },
             {
               "id": 3360,
               "question": "Death in patients with Ludwig's angina is usually due to:",
               "options": ["starvation", "pneumonia", "sepsis", "congestive heart failure", "sudden airway obstruction"],
               "answer": "sudden airway obstruction",
               "answer_index": 4
             },
             {
               "id": 3361,
               "question": "Ranula is a:",
               "options": ["cutaneous ulcer", "mediastinal mass", "parotid cyst", "sublingual cyst", "sublingual node"],
               "answer": "sublingual cyst",
               "answer_index": 3
             },
             {
               "id": 3362,
               "question": "Perleche (fissure of the angle of the mouth) is usually due to:",
               "options": ["candida albicans", "staphylococcus aureus", "escherichia coli", "streptococcus (pneumococcus)", "haemophilus influenzae"],
               "answer": "candida albicans",
               "answer_index": 0
             },
             {
               "id": 3363,
               "question": "The most common cause of recurrent sinusitis is:",
               "options": ["septal deviation", "allergic sinusitis", "nasal polyps", "foreign body", "cystic fibrosis"],
               "answer": "allergic sinusitis",
               "answer_index": 1
             },
             {
               "id": 3364,
               "question": "The most common presentation of acute sinusitis in children is:",
               "options": ["retro - orbital pain", "fever", "headache", "periorbital swelling", "nasal discharge"],
               "answer": "nasal discharge",
               "answer_index": 4
             },
             {
               "id": 3365,
               "question": "The most common infectious disease is:",
               "options": ["toxoplasmosis", "mycoplasmal pneumonia", "acute viral rhinitis", "amebiasis", "measles"],
               "answer": "acute viral rhinitis",
               "answer_index": 2
             },
             {
               "id": 3366,
               "question": "Recurrent otitis media is effectively treated with:",
               "options": ["penicillin / erythromycin", "sulfisoxazole / amoxicillin", "streptomycin / kanamycin", "gentamycin / ampicillin", "tetracycline / chloramphenicol"],
               "answer": "sulfisoxazole / amoxicillin",  
               "answer_index": 1
             },
             {
               "id": 3367,
               "question": "Recurrent otitis media is defined as 3 or more episodes of otitis media within a:",
               "options": ["2 month period", "4 month period", "6 month period", "12 month period", "24 month period"],
               "answer": "6 month period",
               "answer_index": 2
             },
             {
               "id": 3368,
               "question": "The most common ocular disorder in children is:",
               "options": ["uveitis", "conjunctivitis", "retinitis pigmentosa", "blepharitis", "corneal ulcers"],
               "answer": "conjunctivitis",
               "answer_index": 1
             },
             {
               "id": 3369,
               "question": "The most common cause of infectious neonatal conjunctivitis is:",
               "options": ["viral", "gonococcal", "pneumococcal", "chlamydial", "staphylococcal"],
               "answer": "chlamydial",
               "answer_index": 3
             },
             {
               "id": 3370,
               "question": "Granuloma annulare is best treated with:",
               "options": ["corticosteroids", "kwellada", "antibiotics", "radiotherapy", "none of the above"],
               "answer": "corticosteroids",
               "answer_index": 0
             },
             {
               "id": 3371,
               "question": "Lindane (gamma benzene hexachloride, Kwell) is used in treatment of:",
               "options": ["scabies", "tinea versicolor", "herpes simplex", "molluscum contagiosum", "atopic dermatitis"],
               "answer": "scabies",
               "answer_index": 0
             },
             {
               "id": 3372,
               "question": "Which of the following is used in the treatment of cholinergic effects of mushroom poisoning?",
               "options": ["naloxone", "physostigmine", "ethanol", "atropine", "methylene blue"],
               "answer": "atropine",
               "answer_index": 3
             },
             {
               "id": 3373,
               "question": "Carbon monoxide poisoning is treated with:",
               "options": ["naloxone", "physostigmine", "ethanol", "atropine", "oxygen"],
               "answer": "oxygen",
               "answer_index": 4
             },
             {
               "id": 3374,
               "question": "Alopecia/scaly dermatitis are associated with deficiency of:",
               "options": ["vitamin C", "pyridoxine", "pantothenic acid", "biotin", "cyanocobalamin (B12)"],
               "answer": "biotin",
               "answer_index": 3
             },
             {
               "id": 3375,
               "question": "Vitamin E (tocopherols) appears to protect against coronary artery disease, its deficiency is associated with:",
               "options": ["beriberi", "hemorrhage", "osteomalacia", "xerophthalmia", "hemolytic anemia"],
               "answer": "none of the above",
               "answer_index": 4
             },
             {
               "id": 3376,
               "question": "Which of the following is a component of hemoglobin (hematocrit)?",
               "options": ["zinc", "iron", "cobalt", "iodine", "fluorine"],
               "answer": "iron",
               "answer_index": 1
             },
             {
               "id": 3377,
               "question": "Salpingitis (pelvic inflammatory disease/ cervical motion tenderness) in a 20 year old female is best diagnosed by:",
               "options": ["ultrasound", "laparoscopy", "culdocentesis", "uterine biopsy", "urinalysis/cervical gram stain"],
               "answer": "laparoscopy",
               "answer_index": 1
             },
             {
               "id": 3378,
               "question": "The most common complaint of women with pelvic inflammatory disease is:",
               "options": ["fever", "vaginal discharge", "abdominal pain", "dysuria", "excessive menstrual bleeding"],
               "answer": "abdominal pain",
               "answer_index": 2
             },
             {
               "id": 3379,
               "question": "The most common initial presentation of acoustic neuroma is:",
               "options": ["vertigo", "tinnitus", "headache", "ipsilateral deafness", "facial weakness/numbness"],
               "answer": "ipsilateral deafness",  
               "answer_index": 3
             },
             {
               "id": 3380,
               "question": "The most common breast disorder in adolescent girls is:",
               "options": ["intraductal papilloma", "fibroadenoma", "fibrocystic disease", "breast hypertrophy", "carcinoma of the breast"],
               "answer": "fibrocystic disease",
               "answer_index": 2
             },
             {
               "id": 3381,
               "question": "After accidents, the second most common cause of death in adolescents/young adults is:",
               "options": ["suicide", "pneumonia", "infection", "neoplasms", "heart disease"],
               "answer": "suicide",
               "answer_index": 0
             },
             {
               "id": 3382,
               "question": "Diagnosis of necrotizing enterocolitis is confirmed by:",
               "options": ["rectal biopsy", "blood culture", "complete blood count", "presence of pneumatosis intestinalis on X ray", "presence of blood in the stool"],
               "answer": "presence of pneumatosis intestinalis on X ray",
               "answer_index": 3
             },
             {
               "id": 3383,
               "question": "The most common presenting sign in necrotizing enterocolitis is:",
               "options": ["bradycardia", "abdominal distention", "vomiting", "decreased urine output", "increased apnea"],
               "answer": "abdominal distention",
               "answer_index": 1
             },
             {
               "id": 3384,
               "question": "The mortality rate for neonatal meningitis is approximately:",
               "options": ["5%", "10%", "25%", "35%", "50%"],
               "answer": "25%",
               "answer_index": 2
             },
             {
               "id": 3385,
               "question": "The most common cause of neonatal respiratory distress syndrome is:",
               "options": ["meconium aspiration syndrome", "hyaline membrane disease", "spontaneous pneumothorax", "congenital pneumonia", "pleural effusion"],
               "answer": "hyaline membrane disease",
               "answer_index": 1
             },
             {
               "id": 3386,
               "question": "Homonymous hemianopia with macular sparing occurs from cutting the:",
               "options": ["optic nerve", "optic tract", "optic chiasma", "geniculocalcarine tract", "all of the above"],
               "answer": "geniculocalcarine tract",
               "answer_index": 3
             },
             {
               "id": 3387,
               "question": "Which of the following can NOT cross the blood-brain barrier?",
               "options": ["H2O", "CO2 and O2", "protein and cholesterol", "non-ionized (lipid-soluble) drugs", "ionized (non-lipid-soluble) drugs"],
               "answer": "protein and cholesterol",
               "answer_index": 2
             },
             {
               "id": 3388,
               "question": "Respiratory response to exercise result in increased:",
               "options": ["venous Pco2", "O2 consumption", "CO2 production", "ventilation rate", "all of the above"],
               "answer": "all of the above",
               "answer_index": 4
             },
             {
               "id": 3389,
               "question": "Shift of hemoglobin O2 dissociation curve to the left (e.g. fetal hemoglobin / carbon monoxide poisoning) causes increased:",
               "options": ["pH", "Pco2", "2,3 DPG", "temperature", "all of the above"],
               "answer": "pH",
               "answer_index": 0  
             },
             {
               "id": 3390,
               "question": "The most common cause of ophthalmia neonatorum in North America is:",
               "options": ["s. aureus", "chlamydia", "herpes simplex", "silver nitrate use", "neisseria gonococcal"],
               "answer": "chlamydia",
               "answer_index": 1
             },
             {
               "id": 3391,
               "question": "Cholecystokinine (CCK) is a GI hormone which inhibits:",
               "options": ["gastric emptying", "contraction of gallbladder", "pancreatic enzyme secretion", "growth of exocrine pancreas", "all of the above"],
               "answer": "gastric emptying",
               "answer_index": 0
             },
             {
               "id": 3392,
               "question": "Regarding GI motility, the frequency of slow waves is lowest in the stomach and highest in the:",
               "options": ["colon", "ileum", "rectum", "duodenum", "esophagus"],
               "answer": "duodenum",
               "answer_index": 3
             },
             {
               "id": 3393,
               "question": "Which of the following gastric hormones stimulates insulin release?",
               "options": ["gastrin", "secretin", "cholecystokinin (CCK)", "gastric inhibitory peptide (GIP)", "all of the above"],
               "answer": "gastric inhibitory peptide (GIP)",
               "answer_index": 3
             },
             {
               "id": 3394,
               "question": "Which of the following gastric hormones is chemically homologous to glucagon?",
               "options": ["gastrin", "secretin", "cholecystokinin (CCK)", "gastric inhibitory peptide (GIP)", "all of the above"],
               "answer": "secretin",
               "answer_index": 1
             },
             {
               "id": 3395,
               "question": "Which of the following is decreased during hemorrhage?",
               "options": ["angiotensin II", "renin and heart rate", "aldosterone, ADH and TPR", "epinephrine and norepinephrine", "none of the above"],
               "answer": "none of the above",
               "answer_index": 4
             },
             {
               "id": 3396,
               "question": "Parotid gland swellings are malignant in:",
               "options": ["20%", "45%", "60%", "75%", "90%"],
               "answer": "20%",
               "answer_index": 0
             },
             {
               "id": 3397,
               "question": "Submandibular gland swellings are malignant in:",
               "options": ["20%", "45%", "60%", "75%", "90%"],
               "answer": "75%",
               "answer_index": 3
             },
             {
               "id": 3398,
               "question": "Secondary adrenocortical insufficiency:",
               "options": ["causes hyperkalemia", "causes hyperpigmentation", "causes volume contraction", "causes metabolic alkalosis", "is due to primary ACTH deficiency"],
               "answer": "is due to primary ACTH deficiency",
               "answer_index": 4
             },
             {
               "id": 3399,
               "question": "Secretion of growth hormone (somatotropin) is increased by:",
               "options": ["obesity", "pregnancy", "hypoglycemia", "somatostatin", "somatomedins"],
               "answer": "hypoglycemia",
               "answer_index": 2
             },
        {
            "id": 3400,
            "question": "Conn's syndrome (hyperaldosteronism) is characterized by:",
            "options": [
                "hypotension",
                "hyperkalemia",
                "metabolic alkalosis",
                "increased renin secretion",
                "all of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3401,
            "question": "Childhood constipation could be caused by all of the following, EXCEPT:",
            "options": [
                "cerebral palsy",
                "hyperthyroidism",
                "meningomyelocele",
                "central hypotonia",
                "Hirschsprung's disease"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3402,
            "question": "Oat cell cancers of lung and prostate are best treated with:",
            "options": [
                "adenosine",
                "tamoxifen",
                "etoposide",
                "doxorubicin",
                "methotrexate"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3403,
            "question": "Tall stature, long extremities, and dissecting aneurysm risk are features of:",
            "options": [
                "Reye's syndrome",
                "Marfan's syndrome",
                "Beiter's syndrome",
                "Cushing's syndrome",
                "fragile X syndrome"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3404,
            "question": "Fragile X syndrome is characterized by:",
            "options": [
                "X-linked recessive",
                "macroorchidism",
                "long face and jaw",
                "large ears",
                "all of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3405,
            "question": "Which of the following is a risk factor for amniotic fluid embolism?",
            "options": [
                "multiparity",
                "large fetus",
                "rapid labor",
                "late maternal age",
                "all of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3406,
            "question": "Angiomyolipoma (renal hamartoma) is found in approximately 45% to 80% of patients with:",
            "options": [
                "hydrocephalus",
                "achondroplasia",
                "hyperthyroidism",
                "multiple sclerosis",
                "tuberous sclerosis"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3407,
            "question": "Sarcoidosis is associated with:",
            "options": [
                "hypocalcemia",
                "lymphocytosis",
                "increased ESR",
                "hypoglobulinemia",
                "lowered angiotensin converting enzyme"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3408,
            "question": "Regarding antenatal monitoring, fetal bradycardia occurs in all of the following, EXCEPT:",
            "options": [
                "acute cord prolapse",
                "maternal hypotension",
                "uterine hypercontractility",
                "rapid descent during labor",
                "maternal use of sympathomimetics"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3409,
            "question": "Regarding antenatal monitoring, fetal bradycardia occurs in:",
            "options": [
                "maternal fever",
                "chorioamnionitis",
                "acute cord prolapse",
                "fetal or maternal anemia",
                "maternal hyperthyroidism"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3410,
            "question": "Polyhydramnios occurs in:",
            "options": [
                "1/50 deliveries",
                "1/100 deliveries",
                "1/250 deliveries",
                "1/450 deliveries",
                "1/750 deliveries"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3411,
            "question": "The most common cause of premature labor is:",
            "options": [
                "idiopathic",
                "preeclampsia",
                "polyhydramnios",
                "maternal smoking",
                "multiple gestation"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3412,
            "question": "Maternal contraindications to tocolysis (inhibition of uterine contractions) include:",
            "options": [
                "preeclampsia",
                "chorioamnionitis",
                "placenta previa or abruption",
                "diabetes and heart disease",
                "all of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3413,
            "question": "Fetal contraindications to tocolysis include:",
            "options": [
                "fetal distress",
                "multiple gestation",
                "erythroblastosis fetalis",
                "severe congenital anomalies",
                "all of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3414,
            "question": "Which of the following is classified as paraphilia?",
            "options": [
                "fetishism",
                "transvestitism",
                "sexual sadism",
                "exhibitionism",
                "all of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3415,
            "question": "Ramsay Hunt syndrome is associated with lesion mainly in the cranial nerve type:",
            "options": [
                "X (vagus)",
                "VII (facial)",
                "XI (accessory)",
                "IX (glossopharyngeal)",
                "none of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3416,
            "question": "72 year old woman has shingles, she develops sudden, severe facial weakness and pain, the most likely diagnosis is:",
            "options": [
                "Reye's syndrome",
                "Reiter's syndrome",
                "Behcet's syndrome",
                "Ramsay Hunt syndrome",
                "Guillain Barre syndrome"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3417,
            "question": "The most common presentation of bladder carcinoma is:",
            "options": [
                "pain",
                "hematuria",
                "irritation",
                "no symptoms",
                "clot retention"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3418,
            "question": "Adenomyosis (endometrial glands found within the myometrium which occurs in parous women 40-50 years old) is NOT associated with:",
            "options": [
                "dyscoria",
                "dyschezia",
                "dypareunia",
                "menorrhagia",
                "dysmenorrhea"
            ],
            "answer": "a",
            "answer_index": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 3419,
            "question": "Testicular feminization syndrome is associated with:",
            "options": [
                "infertility",
                "short stature",
                "presence of ovaries",
                "normal male phenotype",
                "normal female karyotype"
            ],
            "answer": "a",
            "answer_index": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 3420,
            "question": "Which of the following is a risk factor for ovarian carcinoma?",
            "options": [
                "nulliparity",
                "late menopause",
                "Caucasian race",
                "positive family history",
                "all of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3421,
            "question": "Which of the following is a complication of cesarean section?",
            "options": [
                "infection",
                "hemorrhage",
                "lacerations of the uterus",
                "subsequent rupture of the uterus",
                "all of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3422,
            "question": "Social inhibition, timidity and hypersensitivity to negative evaluation are characteristics of personality disorder type:",
            "options": [
                "avoidant",
                "paranoid",
                "dependent",
                "antisocial",
                "borderline"
            ],
            "answer": "a",
            "answer_index": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 3423,
            "question": "The percentage of the population with the Gilbert's syndrome is:",
            "options": [
                "1%",
                "3%",
                "7%",
                "16%",
                "23%"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3424,
            "question": "If one of the parents has Huntington's disease, the risk of developing the disorder for their children is one in:",
            "options": [
                "2",
                "30",
                "50",
                "75",
                "100"
            ],
            "answer": "a",
            "answer_index": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 3425,
            "question": "The average daily caloric requirement for young people (in kcal/day) is:",
            "options": [
                "1100 for females and 1500 for males",
                "2000 for females and 2700 for males",
                "3200 for females and 3800 for males",
                "4100 for females and 4500 for males",
                "5200 for females and 5600 for males"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
          {
            "id": 3426,
            "question": "The incidence of thalassemia is highest among:",
            "options": [
                "Asians",
                "Afro-Americans",
                "Native Indians",
                "South Americans",
                "Mediterranean decent"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3427,
            "question": "Which of the following cancers is/are more common in Caucasians than in African-Americans?",
            "options": [
                "oral",
                "gastric",
                "laryngeal",
                "esophageal",
                "bladder and renal"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3428,
            "question": "Nulliparity is associated with lower incidence of:",
            "options": [
                "osteoporosis",
                "breast cancer",
                "ovarian cancer",
                "endometrial cancer",
                "pelvic inflammatory disease"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3429,
            "question": "Following are characteristics of carcinoid syndrome (serotonin-secreting, argentaffin cell tumor), EXCEPT:",
            "options": [
                "diarrhea/abdominal pain",
                "bronchoconstriction/dyspnea/wheezing",
                "cutaneous flushing",
                "right sided cardiac valve disease",
                "increased urinary vanillylmandelic acid (VMA)"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3430,
            "question": "Which of the following medications is contraindicated in glaucoma?",
            "options": [
                "diazepam",
                "epinephrine",
                "pilocarpine",
                "timolol maleate",
                "carbonic anhydrase inhibitors"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3431,
            "question": "(Bamboo spine) is a late radiographic sign of:",
            "options": [
                "psoriatic arthritis",
                "osteoporarthritis",
                "rheumatoid arthritis",
                "ankylosing spondylitis",
                "gouty arthritis"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3432,
            "question": "(Wrist drop) is associated with the injury to which of the peripheral nerves?",
            "options": [
                "sciatic",
                "median",
                "ulnar",
                "radial",
                "peroneal"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3433,
            "question": "Capillary hemangioma (strawberry nevus or birthmark) is usually treated with:",
            "options": [
                "fluorouracil (5-FU)",
                "surgical excision",
                "steroid creams",
                "radiotherapy",
                "none of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3432,
            "question": "(Wrist drop) is associated with the injury to which of the peripheral nerves?",
            "options": [
                "sciatic",
                "median",
                "ulnar",
                "radial",
                "peroneal"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3433,
            "question": "Capillary hemangioma (strawberry nevus or birthmark) is usually treated with:",
            "options": [
                "fluorouracil (5-FU)",
                "surgical excision",
                "steroid creams",
                "radiotherapy",
                "none of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3434,
            "question": "Frohlich's syndrome is associated with amenorrhea and:",
            "options": [
                "galactorrhea",
                "gigantism / acromegaly",
                "postpartum hemorrhage / loss of pubic hair",
                "obesity / hirsutism / adipose tissue deposits",
                "sterility / headache / optic atrophy"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3435,
            "question": "Chiari Frommel's syndrome is associated with amenorrhea and:",
            "options": [
                "galactorrhea",
                "gigantism / acromegaly",
                "postpartum hemorrhage / loss of pubic hair",
                "obesity / hirsutism / osteoporosis",
                "sterility / headache / optic atrophy"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3436,
            "question": "Sheehan's syndrome (pituitary necrosis) is associated with amenorrhea and:",
            "options": [
                "galactorrhea",
                "gigantism / acromegaly",
                "postpartum hemorrhage / loss of pubic hair",
                "obesity / hirsutism / hypertension",
                "sterility / headache / optic atrophy"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3437,
            "question": "Basophilic adenoma of pituitary (Cushing's disease) is associated with amenorrhea and:",
            "options": [
                "galactorrhea",
                "gigantism / acromegaly",
                "postpartum hemorrhage / loss of pubic hair",
                "obesity / hirsutism / hypertension / osteoporosis",
                "sterility / headache / optic atrophy"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3438,
            "question": "Acidophilic adenoma of pituitary is associated with amenorrhea and:",
            "options": [
                "galactorrhea / uterine atony",
                "acromegaly / gigantism / bitemporal hemianopsia",
                "postpartum hemorrhage / loss of pubic hair",
                "obesity / hirsutism / osteoporosis",
                "sterility / headache / optic atrophy"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3439,
            "question": "Chromophobe adenoma of the pituitary is most likely to cause amenorrhea and:",
            "options": [
                "hirsutism / osteosarcoma",
                "increased libido / hypotension",
                "postpartum hemorrhage / cardiomegaly",
                "gigantism / acromegaly / bitemporal hemianopsia",
                "hyperprolactinemia / persistent lactation / uterine atony"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3440,
            "question": "Which of the following types of abortions is associated with high incidence of disseminated intravascular coagulation?",
            "options": [
                "missed abortion",
                "inevitable abortion",
                "habitual abortion",
                "incomplete abortion",
                "complete abortion"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3441,
            "question": "At the end of third month of gestation, the fetus weighs:",
            "options": [
                "4 grams",
                "14 grams",
                "140 grams",
                "600 grams",
                "1000 grams"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3442,
            "question": "Podophyllin is contraindicated in pregnancy and used for treatment of lesions smaller than 2 cm caused by:",
            "options": [
                "treponema pallidum",
                "herpesvirus hominis type 1",
                "herpesvirus hominis type 2",
                "human papilloma virus",
                "herpes zoster virus"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3443,
            "question": "The most common cause of herpes genitalis is:",
            "options": [
                "Epstein Barr",
                "herpesvirus hominis type 1",
                "herpesvirus hominis type 2",
                "human papilloma virus",
                "herpes zoster virus"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3444,
            "question": "Following are risk factors for endometrial carcinoma, EXCEPT:",
            "options": [
                "obesity",
                "diabetes mellitus",
                "hypertension",
                "prolonged use of estrogens",
                "prolonged use of oral contraceptives"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3445,
            "question": "Following are absolute contraindications for birth control pills, EXCEPT:",
            "options": [
                "coronary artery disease",
                "diabetes mellitus",
                "impaired hepatic function",
                "thromboembolic disease",
                "breast cancer"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3446,
            "question": "The initial treatment of choriocarcinoma is:",
            "options": [
                "estrogens",
                "tamoxifen",
                "methotrexate",
                "radiotherapy",
                "hysterectomy"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3447,
            "question": "Which of the following is used to confirm the diagnosis of gonorrhea?",
            "options": [
                "urinalysis",
                "Frei test",
                "Papanicolau smear",
                "darkfield examination",
                "Thayer Martin medium"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3448,
            "question": "The most common complication of ovarian cyst is:",
            "options": [
                "rupture",
                "torsion",
                "intestinal obstruction",
                "peritonitis",
                "malignant transformation"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3449,
            "question": "Rectal strictures may be found in females and homosexual males with:",
            "options": [
                "genital warts",
                "lymphogranuloma venereum",
                "chancroid",
                "gonorrhea",
                "granuloma inguinale"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3450,
            "question": "Donovan bodies are found in:",
            "options": [
                "syphilis",
                "lymphogranuloma venereum",
                "chancroid",
                "gonorrhea",
                "granuloma inguinale"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3451,
            "question": "White cheesy or curd-like, adherent vaginal discharge is seen in:",
            "options": [
                "gonorrhea",
                "genital candidiasis",
                "trichomoniasis",
                "syphilis",
                "granuloma inguinale"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3452,
            "question": "Green-yellow/frothy/malodorous vaginal discharge is most likely to be caused by:",
            "options": [
                "gonorrhea",
                "genital candidiasis",
                "trichomoniasis",
                "syphilis",
                "granuloma inguinale"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3453,
            "question": "The incidence of appendiceal perforation in children with acute appendicitis is:",
            "options": [
                "2%",
                "5%",
                "10%",
                "15%",
                "40%"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3454,
            "question": "Aortoiliac occlusive disease (LeRiche's syndrome) is best diagnosed by:",
            "options": [
                "ultrasound",
                "aortography",
                "abdominal X ray",
                "aortic wall biopsy",
                "abdominal CT scan"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3455,
            "question": "The incidence of colorectal carcinoma in patients with familial polyposis is:",
            "options": [
                "10%",
                "30%",
                "50%",
                "80%",
                "100%"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3456,
            "question": "Neuroleptic malignant syndrome may be caused by:",
            "options": [
                "amantidine",
                "levodopa",
                "bromocriptine",
                "dantrolene",
                "tricyclic antidepressants"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3457,
            "question": "Mortality rate for neuroleptic malignant syndrome is about:",
            "options": [
                "1%",
                "5%",
                "10%",
                "20%",
                "40%"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3458,
            "question": "Following are drugs used in treatment of Parkinson's disease, EXCEPT:",
            "options": [
                "benztropine / cycrimine",
                "amitriptyline / imipramine",
                "bromocriptine / ethiopropazine",
                "trihexyphenidyl / biperiden",
                "levodopa / chlorphenoxamine"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3459,
            "question": "The drug of choice for pneumocystis carinii pneumonitis (pneumocytosis) is:",
            "options": [
                "corticosteroids",
                "clindamycin",
                "pyrimethamine",
                "trimethoprim sulphamethoxazole",
                "tetracycline"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3460,
            "question": "Rabies immune globulin is recommended for all:",
            "options": [
                "close personal contacts with hepatitis A",
                "health care personnel",
                "pregnant women",
                "individuals bitten by wild animals",
                "individuals with meningococcal meningitis"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3461,
            "question": "Slow/deep respiration (Kussmaul breathing) is a characteristic of:",
            "options": [
                "cystic fibrosis",
                "bronchial asthma",
                "diabetic ketoacidosis",
                "respiratory distress syndrome",
                "chronic obstructive lung disease"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3462,
            "question": "Shyness/timidity/loneliness/social discomfort/fear of rejection are seen in personality disorder type:",
            "options": [
                "avoidant",
                "paranoid",
                "dependent",
                "antisocial",
                "borderline"
            ],
            "answer": "a",
            "answer_index": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 3463,
            "question": "Which of the following personality disorders occurs almost exclusively in women?",
            "options": [
                "avoidant",
                "histerionic (hysterical)",
                "dependent",
                "schizotypal",
                "passive-aggressive"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3464,
            "question": "Morphea (dermal fibrosis producing plaques of thickened skin) is associated with:",
            "options": [
                "dermatomyositis (polymyositis)",
                "polyarteritis nodosa",
                "rheumatoid arthritis",
                "scleroderma (systemic sclerosis)",
                "systemic lupus erythematosus"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3465,
            "question": "The most common cancer in Caucasians is the cancer of:",
            "options": [
                "lung",
                "colon",
                "skin",
                "liver",
                "kidney"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3466,
            "question": "Increased human chorionic gonadotropin (hCG) after pregnancy may suggest the diagnosis of:",
            "options": [
                "carcinoma of the cervix",
                "uterine choriocarcinoma/hydatidiform mole",
                "carcinoma of the uterine corpus",
                "granulosa cell tumor of the ovary",
                "anencephalic pregnancy"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3467,
            "question": "Sepsis (septicemia) in abruptio placentae is usually due to:",
            "options": [
                "listeria monocytogen",
                "clostridium perfringens",
                "clostridium difficile",
                "staphylococcus vaginalis",
                "neisseria gonorrheae"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3468,
            "question": "Dilatation and curettage (D and C) is most useful in women with:",
            "options": [
                "vulvar pruritus",
                "postcoital bleeding",
                "abdominal distention",
                "postmenopausal bleeding",
                "postcoital abdominal pain"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3469,
            "question": "Fetal meningomyelocele is best detected by:",
            "options": [
                "amniotic fluid alpha fetoprotein (AFT)",
                "amniotic fluid chromosomal study",
                "maternal urinary estirol",
                "fetal blood sampling",
                "none of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "a",
            "answer_index": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 3470,
            "question": "The main symptom in children with methemoglobulinemia is hypoxia and:",
            "options": [
                "abdominal distention",
                "skin rash",
                "diarrhea",
                "cyanosis",
                "edema"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3471,
            "question": "In acute adrenal insufficiency (Addisonian crisis), positive blood culture usually indicates the presence of:",
            "options": [
                "streptococci",
                "staphylococci",
                "meningococci",
                "gonococci",
                "haemophilus influenzae"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3472,
            "question": "Following are associated with acute adrenal insufficiency (Addisonian crisis), EXCEPT:",
            "options": [
                "lymphadenopathy",
                "high fever",
                "petechiae",
                "abnormal skin pigmentation",
                "hyperglycemia/alkalosis"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3473,
            "question": "Subclavian artery compression in cervical rib compression is ruled out by:",
            "options": [
                "Brodie Trendelenburg test",
                "Allen test",
                "Schwartz test",
                "Adson's test",
                "Tinel's test"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3474,
            "question": "The most common nosocomial infection is:",
            "options": [
                "urinary tract infection",
                "surgical wound infection",
                "respiratory tract infection",
                "hepatobiliary tract infection",
                "gastrointestinal tract infection"
            ],
            "answer": "a",
            "answer_index": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 3475,
            "question": "Maternal tetracycline therapy is associated with fetal:",
            "options": [
                "blindness",
                "gray baby syndrome",
                "aplastic anemia",
                "teeth discoloration",
                "kernicterus"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3476,
            "question": "Gray baby syndrome is a circulatory collapse that can occur in premature and newborn infants receiving large doses of:",
            "options": [
                "tetracycline",
                "streptomycin",
                "griseofulvin",
                "erythromycin",
                "chloramphenicol"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3477,
            "question": "Which of the following hepatic tumors occurs almost exclusively in men?",
            "options": [
                "hemangioma",
                "adenoma",
                "focal nodular hyperplasia",
                "primary liver cancer",
                "none of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3478,
            "question": "Tardive dyskinesia (more common in women/can be treated with reserpine) may occur after at least 6 months of treatment with:",
            "options": [
                "lithium",
                "tricyclic antidepressants",
                "anxiolytic agents (sedatives)",
                "antipsychotics (neuroleptics)",
                "carbamazepine"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3479,
            "question": "Familial Mediterranean fever is caused by:",
            "options": [
                "virus",
                "anaerobic bacillus",
                "rickettsia",
                "spirochete",
                "uncertain etiology"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3480,
            "question": "Anthrax is caused by:",
            "options": [
                "aerobic bacilli",
                "anaerobic bacilli",
                "gram positive cocci",
                "gram positive bacilli",
                "spirochetes"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3481,
            "question": "Leptospirosis is also known as Weil's disease or icterohemorrhagic fever which is caused by:",
            "options": [
                "spirochetes",
                "anaerobic bacilli",
                "rickettsias",
                "parasites",
                "viruses"
            ],
            "answer": "a",
            "answer_index": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 3482,
            "question": "Which of the following is LEAST likely to be seen in Reiter's syndrome?",
            "options": [
                "stomatitis",
                "carditis/aortic regurgitation",
                "dactylitis (sausage digits)",
                "hepatosplenomegaly",
                "keratoderma blennorhagica"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3483,
            "question": "Following are features of Gaucher's disease, EXCEPT:",
            "options": [
                "hepatomegaly/protuberant abdomen",
                "Gaucher's cells in marrow/seizures",
                "bone and joint pain/anemia/lethargy",
                "increased serum cholesterol",
                "increased serum acid phosphatase/thrombocytopenia"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3484,
            "question": "Antidote for dipyridamole (persantine) overdose is:",
            "options": [
                "atropine",
                "aminophylline",
                "nitrate",
                "naloxolone",
                "chlorpromazine"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3485,
            "question": "Wegener's granulomatosis is best treated with:",
            "options": [
                "amantidine",
                "azathioprine",
                "prednisone",
                "thiazide",
                "cyclophosphamide"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3486,
            "question": "Which of the following is LEAST likely to be involved in Wegener's granulomatosis?",
            "options": [
                "spleen",
                "kidney",
                "middle ear",
                "sinuses",
                "lung"
            ],
            "answer": "a",
            "answer_index": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 3487,
            "question": "TORCH syndrome (TORCH complex) refers to all of the following disorders, EXCEPT:",
            "options": [
                "toxoplasmosis",
                "rubella",
                "cytomegalic inclusion disease",
                "infectious mononucleosis",
                "syphilis/herpes simplex virus"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3488,
            "question": "The most important initial diagnostic procedure for a one year old child with seizures is:",
            "options": [
                "EEG",
                "arterial blood gases",
                "CT scan of the head",
                "spinal tap",
                "brain X ray"
            ],
            "answer": "a",
            "answer_index": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 3489,
            "question": "Simple febrile seizures (febrile convulsion syndrome) most commonly occur between ages:",
            "options": [
                "2 weeks to 2 months",
                "2 to 6 months",
                "6 months to 3 years",
                "5 to 10 years",
                "10 to 15 years"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3490,
            "question": "Flexion deformity of the proximal interphalangeal joint is seen in:",
            "options": [
                "Boxer's fracture",
                "Dupuytren's contracture",
                "Mallet's finger",
                "carpal tunnel syndrome",
                "Boutonniere deformity"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3491,
            "question": "Patent ductus arteriosus is kept open by:",
            "options": [
                "histamine",
                "indomethacin",
                "catecholamines",
                "acetylcholine",
                "prostaglandins"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3492,
            "question": "Following promote the closure of patent ductus arteriosus, EXCEPT:",
            "options": [
                "histamine",
                "indomethacin",
                "catecholamines",
                "acetylcholine",
                "prostaglandins"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 3493,
            "question": "In term infants, patent ductus arteriosus usually closes:",
            "options": [
                "immediately after birth",
                "24 hours after birth",
                "1 to 3 days after birth",
                "8 to 15 days after birth",
                "during the last month of pregnancy"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3494,
            "question": "Pheochromocytoma/neuroblastoma are associated with increased urinary:",
            "options": [
                "5 hydroxyindoleacetic acid (5 HIAA)",
                "vanillylmandelic acid (VMA)",
                "urobilinogen",
                "aldosterone",
                "hydroxyproline"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3495,
            "question": "The most common soft tissue malignant tumor in adults is:",
            "options": [
                "liposarcoma",
                "fibrosarcoma",
                "neurofibrosarcoma",
                "rhabdomyosarcoma",
                "synoviosarcoma"
            ],
            "answer": "a",
            "answer_index": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 3496,
            "question": "The most common soft tissue malignant tumor in children is:",
            "options": [
                "liposarcoma",
                "fibrosarcoma",
                "neurofibrosarcoma",
                "rhabdomyosarcoma",
                "synoviosarcoma"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3497,
            "question": "The usual site of Ewing's sarcoma is:",
            "options": [
                "periosteum",
                "epiphysis",
                "metaphysis",
                "diaphysis",
                "articular cartilage"
            ],
            "answer": "d",
            "answer_index": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 3498,
            "question": "Bone X ray in bronchogenic carcinoma characteristically shows:",
            "options": [
                "aneurysmal bone cyst",
                "hypertrophic osteoarthropathy",
                "linear calcifications",
                "bony erosions/osteophytes",
                "generalized demineralization"
            ],
            "answer": "b",
            "answer_index": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3499,
            "question": "The initial complaint of patients with Paget's disease of bone usually is:",
            "options": [
                "deafness",
                "palpitations",
                "bone pain",
                "bowing of legs",
                "paraplegia"
            ],
            "answer": "c",
            "answer_index": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3500,
            "question": "Following are causes or predisposing factors for osteoporosis, EXCEPT:",
            "options": [
                "rheumatoid arthritis",
                "Cushing's syndrome",
                "homocystinuria",
                "steroid therapy",
                "multiparity"
            ],
            "answer": "e",
            "answer_index": 4
        }
    ]
 }